<?xml version = "1.0" encoding = "utf-8"?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Creatures of the Yokai Realms</name>
        <update version = "0.0.2">
            <file name = "creatures-of-the-yokai-realms.xml" url = "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/StrangeMeta/homebrew/main/ryokos-guide-to-the-yokai-realms/Creatures/creatures-of-the-yokai-realms.xml"/>
        </update>
    </info>

    <!-- Creatures of the Yokai Realms -->
	<element name = "Aspect of Ashura" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_ASPECT_OF_ASHURA">
		<description>
            <p>A favoured subject among poets and thespians across the realms is the tale of Ashura: the three-faced, six-armed demon god of destruction cast down from the heavens by the deities he offended. While the legend of Ashura might end there, his legacy and demonic power endure. Stories shared in hushed, fireside whispers tell of mighty Fiends that befoul the land—creatures echoing the form and power of the defeated demon god. On a path fueled by zealous passion and hate-driven vengeance, they cleave down everything in their way. The original Ashura may be gone, but the aspects of Ashura carry his legacy into the mortal world.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Fragment of Fury. </strong>Aeons ago, upon his defeat, Ashura was broken and scattered to different parts of the world, his power contained and fragmented. Over the centuries, however, like the creeping rust that shatters iron chains, time has weakened these seals, and aspects of Ashura have manifested across the realms. While a mere echo of the true Ashura, these creatures are deadly and cunning, inheriting fearsome magic, deadly battle prowess, and a burning wrath.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Blood and Lust. </strong>Similar to the original Ashura, the aspects are creatures whose body and mind are set ablaze by the most intense emotions one could feel. Happiness is experienced as nothing less than dizzying ecstasy, anger as nothing less than blinding rage. When met in battle, there is no hope of mercy, surrender, or compromise, and only death can stop them.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Large Fiend (Yokai), Chaotic Evil</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 17 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 157 (15d10 + 75)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 50ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +5</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>24 (+7)</td><td>20 (+5)</td><td>20 (+5)</td><td>18 (+4)</td><td>9 (-1)</td><td>10 (+0)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Saving Throws</strong> Dex +10, Wis +4, Cha +5</li>
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Arcana +7, Athletics +17, Perception +9</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> cold, fire; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from non-magical attacks</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> charmed, exhaustion, frightened, paralyzed, poisoned, stunned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 19</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> Abyssal, Common, telepathy 120ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 13 (10,000 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Critical Wound.</em></strong> When the aspect hits a creature with six or more attack rolls on a single turn, that creature’s hit point maximum is reduced by 11 (1d8 + 7). This reduction can’t be undone by any means short of a wish spell.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Reckless.</em></strong> At the start of its turn, the aspect can gain advantage on all melee weapon attack rolls until the start of its next turn, but attack rolls against it have advantage until then.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Three Heads.</em></strong> The aspect can take up to three reactions per round, but only one per turn. It can’t use the same reaction option more than once each round.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Legendary Resistance (3/Day).</em></strong> If the aspect fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The aspect makes six Longsword attacks.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Bite.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (1d6 + 7) piercing damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Longsword.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (1d8 + 7) slashing damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Ashura's Grasp.</em></strong> The aspect lets loose a burst of grasping conjuration magic, forcing one creature it can see within 300 feet of it to make a DC 18 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes 65 (10d12) force damage and is teleported to an unoccupied space the aspect can see within 20 feet of the aspect. On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage and isn’t teleported.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Reactions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Nip.</em></strong> When a creature ends its turn within 5 feet of the aspect, the aspect makes one Bite attack against that creature.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Goad.</em></strong> When a creature the aspect can see misses an attack roll or fails an ability check or saving throw, the aspect hurls a magically infused insult at that creature. The target must succeed on a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or use its reaction to move its speed toward the aspect. If a creature moves within 5 feet of the aspect in this way, it can make one melee weapon attack against the aspect as a part of its reaction.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Spell Swallow.</em></strong> When a creature the aspect can see within 120 feet of it casts a spell, the aspect attempts to duplicate that magic for itself. The creature must make a DC 18 Charisma saving throw. On a failure, the spell is cast as usual, but the aspect also casts that same spell as a part of this reaction.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Bakezori" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_BAKEZORI">
		<description>
            <p>A crowd erupts in cheers as a group of students dash by on a track, each desperately sprinting forward, hellbent on outrunning the rest. As they round the final turn, a girl wearing a pair of shoddy-looking sandals pulls ahead, moving with a nimbleness and speed that onlookers could swear she did not previously possess. Later, in secret, after taking home a gleaming trophy, the girl removes her footwear and thanks them quietly, extending a handful of straw. A single eye opens up on each sandal, and a pair of bakezōri reveal themselves, grinning with delight as they take a meal from their human friend.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Preferential Possession. </strong>As a subspecies of tsukumogami—spirits that like to possess inanimate objects—thebakezōri are unusual in that they exclusively seek out footwear to inhabit. Like most tsukumogami, they are most attracted to objects that have gone through an interesting life of their own; it is common for a pair of bakezōri to settle themselves in frayed, damaged sandals. As with all sentient creatures, however, they are known to have idiosyncrasies and preferences and can be convinced to possess a new, shiny piece of footwear at the behest of a friendly adventurer.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Urban Yokai. </strong>Bakezōri are among the most common yokai for average Humanoids to encounter and are viewed as pests rather than outright threats. They tend to gravitate toward larger communities due to their possession preferences but prefer to remain hidden from the eyes of strangers, indistinguishable from a ruined sandal while resting by the side of the road.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Tiny Fey (Yokai), Chaotic Neutral</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 12</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 7 (2d4 + 2)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 40ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +2</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>8 (-1)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>12 (+1)</td><td>7 (-2)</td><td>10 (+0)</td><td>12 (+1)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Perception +2</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from non-magical attacks</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 12</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 1/4 (50 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Bakezoomies.</em></strong> While a willing bakezōri is worn by a creature with feet, that creature’s walking speed is increased by 15 feet.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Flip-Flop Chomp.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4 + 2) piercing damage. If the target is a creature with feet, it must make a DC 12 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the bakezōri attaches itself to the creature’s foot. The bakezōri can detach itself by spending 5 feet of its movement. While attached to a creature in this way, the bakezōri has advantage on attack rolls against the creature, moves with the creature, can’t attack other creatures, and the creature’s speed is reduced by 15 feet. The creature can use an action to make a DC 11 Strength check, removing the bakezōri on a success, where it lands prone in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the creature.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Your Sole Is Mine.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature that the bakezōri is attached to. Hit: 11 (2d8 + 2) piercing damage.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Betobeto-san" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_ASPECT_OF_BETOBETO_SAN">
		<description>
            <p>Among the ranks of city-dwelling yokai, the mischievous betobeto-san is one of paradoxical reputation—simultaneously infamous for inspiring fear in the hearts of those who encounter it, yet well-loved by locals as a playful, prankster spirit. Most of the time, the betobeto-san is invisible, but should one choose to reveal itself, onlookers are greeted with the sight of a round, ball-like creature with a grinning maw and two small legs. It is known to enjoy wearing sandals, with the tell-tale echo of invisible feet pitter-pattering over cobbled stone a sure indication that the betobeto-san is near.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>One Step at a Time. </strong>The betobeto-san is nocturnal, emerging from its hidden nest to roam the empty streets after most citizens have gone to sleep. Every city has stragglers, transients, and hooligans who walk the town at night, making perfect prey for the knavish yokai. The betobeto-san  follows closely behind its quarry, its footsteps echoing into the darkness, but when its victim turns to look, they find themselves to be seemingly alone. Isolated in the darkness and haunted by echoing footsteps, victims grow increasingly fearful—a fear that the betobeto-san is eager to exacerbate; fear is its prize.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Scary Sustenance. </strong>Betobeto-san sustain themselves on a diet of fear, but unless the impish yokai wishes it, their prey is not truly harmed in this process. In fact, their ability to devour fright has become revered by civilians and adventurers alike, with some attempting to tame and train betobeto-san to aid in soothing the emotions of those suffering from extreme stress and nightmares. However, in communities where fear is an ever-present spectre, perhaps under the reign of a cruel tyrant or in times of famine and war, these small yokai become corrupted by the persistent atmosphere of dread. Such betobeto-san grow huge as they feast aggressively and without caution, devouring a portion of their victims’ souls in the process. These betobeto-sama are cruel and dangerous, their mere presence perpetuating the dread that birthed them within desperate, haunted communities.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Small Fey (Yokai), Chaotic Neutral</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 13 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 19 (3d6 + 9)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 30ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +2</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>12 (+1)</td><td>12 (+1)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>9 (-1)</td><td>13 (+1)</td><td>10 (+0)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from non-magical attacks</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> frightened</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 11</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 1/2 (100 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Surprise!</em></strong> If the betobeto-san is invisible when it rolls initiative, it can choose to turn visible. If it does so, each creature within 10 feet of the betobeto-san that can see it must succeed on a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of it for 1 minute. A creature can repeat this save at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Slam.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6 + 3) bludgeoning damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Devour Fear.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one frightened creature. Hit: 9 (2d8) piercing damage. When a frightened creature is damaged by this attack, it gains immunity to the frightened condition for the next hour as the betobeto-san devours its terror.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Sneak.</em></strong> The betobeto-san magically turns invisible until the end of its next turn or until immediately after it makes an attack.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Jump Scare.</em></strong> The betobeto-san attempts to frighten one creature it can see within 30 feet of it. That creature must succeed on a DC13 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of the betobeto-san for 1 minute. A creature can repeat this save at the end of its turn, ending the effect on a success. If a creature’s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the betobeto-san’s Jump Scare for the next 24 hours.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Betobeto-sama" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_ASPECT_OF_BETOBETO_SAMA">
		<description>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Huge Fey (Yokai), Chaotic Evil</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 13 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 200 (16d12 + 96)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 30ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +4</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>26 (+8)</td><td>9 (-1)</td><td>22 (+6)</td><td>9 (-1)</td><td>13 (+1)</td><td>10 (+0)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Saving Throws</strong> Str +12, Wis +5</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> cold, necrotic; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from non-magical attacks</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> exhaustion, frightened</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> blindsight 30ft., darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 19</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 9 (5,000 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Surprise!</em></strong> If the betobeto-sama is invisible when it rolls initiative, it can choose to turn visible. If it does so, each creature within 60 feet of the betobeto-sama that can see it must succeed on a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for for 1 minute. A creature can repeat this save at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>True Terror.</em></strong> A creature frightened by the betobeto-sama has disadvantage on Intelligence and Wisdom saving throws and on saving throws made to maintain concentration. </li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The betobeto-sama makes two attacks with any combination of Betobeto-sama Slam and Feast of Fear.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Betobeto-sama Slam.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 24 (3d10 + 8) bludgeoning damage. If the target is a creature that isn’t frightened, it must succeed on a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of the betobeto-sama for 1 minute. If the target is a frightened creature, it must succeed on a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or become stunned until it is no longer frightened. A creature can repeat this save at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Feast of Fear.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 10 ft., one stunned and frightened creature. Hit: 26 (4d8 + 8) piercing damage, and the target’s Charisma score is reduced by 1d4. The target dies if this reduces its Charisma to 0. Otherwise, the reduction lasts until the target finishes a short or long rest.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Betobeto-sama Sneak.</em></strong> The betobeto-sama magically turns invisible until the end of its next turn or until immediately after it makes an attack.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Dodomeki" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_DODOMEKI">
		<description>
            <p>Greed incarnate, the dodomeki are covetous, fiendish yokai infatuated with wealth and thievery. They take a distorted, humanoid form, with flesh covered in twitching, bulging eyes as black as a starless night. Their arms are grotesquely extended, their hair grows long and dark, and their grasping claws are vicious and swift.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Deadly Treasure Hunters. </strong>Dodomeki stalk those who radiate the stench of affluence, which dodomeki detect as a sickly, sweet aroma. Cloaked by invisibility and aided by a supernatural stealth, they brazenly pick the pockets of nobles in broad daylight, retreating before their theft is detected. Should a wealthy merchant or courier with an expensive cargo be caught alone, a dodomeki will reveal itself, reveling in cruel slaughter before meticulously stripping the corpse of all valuable possessions.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Insatiable Avarice. </strong>Devourers of treasure, dodomeki do not keep hordes as dragons do. Their hunger for wealth is insatiable, but although they typically target gold, a dodomeki can covet and consume any object that inspires avarice in others. Because they target only those bearing riches, some impoverished communities view their existence as divine retribution for those who wield financial dominion over others.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Medium Fiend (Yokai), Neutral Evil</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 14 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 102 (12d8 + 48)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 40ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +3</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>16 (+3)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>18 (+4)</td><td>11 (+0)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>12 (+1)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Perception +8, Sleight of Hand +9, Stealth +9</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 18</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> Abyssal, Common</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 5 (1,800 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Wealthsense.</em></strong> The dodomeki can sense the direction of any valuable objects within 100 feet of it, including behind total cover, as a saccharine aroma. The greater the greed an object inspires in others, the more potent the stench.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Grasping Thief.</em></strong> The first time the dodomeki hits a creature with its Wrenching Claw attack on its turn, it steals coins that the creature is carrying worth a total value in gold pieces equal to ten times the slashing damage dealt.</li>
                <p></p>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The dodomeki makes two Wrenching Claw attacks.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Wrenching Claw.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 12 (2d8 + 3) slashing damage plus 5 (1d10) psychic damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Revel in Gold.</em></strong> The dodomeki magically feasts on any treasure it is carrying, causing it to disintegrate into motes of golden light. The dodomeki gains 1 temporary hit point for every 10 gold pieces worth of objects it devours in this way, up to a maximum of 25 temporary hit points.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Thieves' Blessing.</em></strong> The dodomeki magically turns invisible for 1 minute or until it attacks or its concentration ends (as if concentrating on a spell). Any equipment the dodomeki wears or carries is invisible with it.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Dorotabo" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_DOROTABO">
		<description>
            <p>A band of inquisitive boys crawl under hedgerows and over fences beyond a long-abandoned track road leading out of town, ignoring the flaking, painted warning signs plastered over along the road. As they heedlessly traipse across an abandoned rice field of mud and wilted plants, the earth suddenly shifts beneath them. In horror, the trespassers stand transfixed as a humanoid figure rises from the muck, coated in soil and withered vines, its three fingers pointing accusingly at the intruders. Only upon coming face to face with the slouching, decrepit form of the dorotabō do the interlopers realise the folly of insatiable curiosity.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Product of Hardwork. </strong>Akin to the onryō, dorotabō are vengeful spirits borne of the intense anguish of the dead. Unlike onryō however, who were warriors in life, dorotabō were once common farmers. When a field is desecrated by damage or neglect after the passing of its caretaker, the spirit of the one who once toiled so dutifully there becomes corrupted with anger and malice, transforming into a dorotabō, now cursed to haunt the land they once loved.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Tied to the Land. </strong>Dorotabō are intimately tied to their land; they are unwilling—and unable—to step foot outside of its borders. Within their territory, they are able to manipulate the earth itself, conjuring decay-ridden plants to entangle trespassers and bury them among the other foolish dead. They are grim guardians, and their domination is absolute across their tiny kingdom, for who can know the land better than the farmer it once belonged to?</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Medium Undead (Yokai), Lawful Evil</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 15 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 82 (11d8 + 33)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 30ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +3</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>16 (+3)</td><td>11 (+0)</td><td>17 (+3)</td><td>9 (-1)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>10 (+0)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Nature +5</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> cold, necrotic; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from non-magical attacks</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> exhaustion, frightened, poisoned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 13</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> the languages it knew in life</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 5 (1,800 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>One With the Land.</em></strong> The dorotabō ignores difficult terrain caused by magical and nonmagical plants, mud, swamps, or other natural phenomena.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The dorotabō makes three attacks with any combination of Three-Fingered Claw and Wrathful Scythe.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Three-Fingered Claw.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (3d4 + 3) slashing damage, and the target must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw or be poisoned for 1 minute.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Wrathful Scythe.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d12 + 3) slashing damage, and the area within 10 feet of the dorotabō becomes difficult terrain as sickly, grasping plants manifest beneath the arc of the scythe. These plants wither and fade 10 minutes after appearing.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Vengeful Earth (3/Day).</em></strong> Up to three creatures standing on an area of earth within 60 feet of the dorotabō that it can see are besieged by mouldering vines that burst from the ground at their feet. Each creature must make a DC 14 Strength saving throw or be restrained for 1 minute. A restrained creature can use its action to make a DC 14 Strength (Athletics) check, ending the effect on itself on a success. A creature can also attack the vines to destroy them, which have an AC of 12, 10 hit points, immunity to necrotic damage, and vulnerability to fire damage.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Ebi'Ishi" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_EBIISHI">
		<description>
            <h5>Ebizo</h5>
            <p>Far beneath roiling ocean waves, in pitch darkness and numbing cold, only the hardiest and most tenacious life forms endure. The Ebizo, a society of dangerous crustacean yokai, are notorious for their raids on coastal towns and the plundering of ships foolhardy enough to stray into their ocean territory. According to legend, in aeons past, they were once isetsu who threw off the shackles of divine imperative, forsaking their post on land and stepping willingly into the ocean’s embrace. There, beneath the crushing pressure of ten-thousand fathoms, their shells and hearts hardened in the deep, endless dark. If the tales of their origin hold true, the irony is not lost on the isetsu; these ancient cousins, who abandoned their roles as guardians of the shoreline, have become monstrous yokai, chief among its greatest threats.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Current Affairs. </strong>Despite their clunky, encumbered appearance, none can navigate riptides and ride currents quite like the Ebizo—reading and sensing the flow of the water with a precision reminiscent of a hawk gliding on an updraft. While uncontested combatants in water, they are still formidable and ferocious on land, carrying the power and tenacity of the ocean wherever they tread.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Society. </strong>Contrary to the stories told by landfolk, to whom the Ebizo are naught but bloodthirsty pirates and conquerors, Ebizo society is rich and complex. The primary yokai of the clan are ebi’ishi, kanibozu, and zuwai, each with distinct talents and cultural importance. Although much of Ebizo society is crafted around oceanic conquest and battles with landfolk, they also engage in festivals, art, religion, and industry. Ebizo are intelligent and articulate, capable of reason and compromise, and, while undoubtedly deadly and aggressive, aren’t devoid of kindness and mercy.</p>
            <p></p>
            <h4>Ebi'Ishi</h4>
            <p>The bulk of the Ebizo clan’s warriors are ebi’ishi—hardy lobster yokai with natural carapaces as durable as lacquered armour. Their roles range from city guards to infantry soldiers, while elder ebi’ishi serve as elite juggernauts tasked with the defence of zuwai. With experience comes strength and wisdom, an adage that rings particularly true among the ebi’ishi, for they never cease growing. Over time, their shells and claws become increasingly thick and mighty, with elders bearing carapaces so dense they deflect weapons with the ease of waves breaking on rock. However, as their weight and strength increase, their mobility suffers. The ultimate fate of an ebi’ishi is for their carapace to grow so heavy that it crushes the flesh within. To collapse under the weight of one’s shell is seen as an honourable death for an otherwise unconquerable warrior of the Ebizo clan.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Medium Fiend (Yokai), Lawful Evil</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 17 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 120 (16d8 + 48)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 30ft., swim 60ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +3</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>18 (+4)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>9 (-1)</td><td>10 (+0)</td><td>12 (+1)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Athletics +6</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> cold, poison</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> blindsight 10ft., darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 10</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> Aquan, Common</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 4 (1,100 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The ebi’ishi makes two attacks with any combination of Claw and Spear</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Claw.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 13 (2d8 + 4) piercing damage. Instead of dealing damage, the ebi’ishi can grapple the target (escape DC 16). Either way, if the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 14 Strength saving throw or drop whatever it’s holding.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Spear.</em></strong> Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d6 + 4) piercing damage.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Ink Spray (Recharge 4-6).</em></strong> The ebi’ishi hurls a glob of ink at one creature it can see within 20 feet of itself. The target must succeed on a DC 13 Constitution saving throw or be blinded until the end of its next turn. While underwater, the ebi’ishi instead expels an ink cloud in a 10-foot radius. The cloud spreads around corners and heavily obscures the area. Each creature other than the ebi’ishi that ends its turn there must make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw, taking 16 (3d10) poison damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. A strong current disperses the ink cloud, which otherwise disappears at the end of the ebi’ishi’s next turn.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Ebi'Ishi Elder" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_EBIISHI_ELDER">
		<description>
            <h5>Ebizo</h5>
            <p>Far beneath roiling ocean waves, in pitch darkness and numbing cold, only the hardiest and most tenacious life forms endure. The Ebizo, a society of dangerous crustacean yokai, are notorious for their raids on coastal towns and the plundering of ships foolhardy enough to stray into their ocean territory. According to legend, in aeons past, they were once isetsu who threw off the shackles of divine imperative, forsaking their post on land and stepping willingly into the ocean’s embrace. There, beneath the crushing pressure of ten-thousand fathoms, their shells and hearts hardened in the deep, endless dark. If the tales of their origin hold true, the irony is not lost on the isetsu; these ancient cousins, who abandoned their roles as guardians of the shoreline, have become monstrous yokai, chief among its greatest threats.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Current Affairs. </strong>Despite their clunky, encumbered appearance, none can navigate riptides and ride currents quite like the Ebizo—reading and sensing the flow of the water with a precision reminiscent of a hawk gliding on an updraft. While uncontested combatants in water, they are still formidable and ferocious on land, carrying the power and tenacity of the ocean wherever they tread.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Society. </strong>Contrary to the stories told by landfolk, to whom the Ebizo are naught but bloodthirsty pirates and conquerors, Ebizo society is rich and complex. The primary yokai of the clan are ebi’ishi, kanibozu, and zuwai, each with distinct talents and cultural importance. Although much of Ebizo society is crafted around oceanic conquest and battles with landfolk, they also engage in festivals, art, religion, and industry. Ebizo are intelligent and articulate, capable of reason and compromise, and, while undoubtedly deadly and aggressive, aren’t devoid of kindness and mercy.</p>
            <p></p>
            <h4>Ebi'Ishi</h4>
            <p>The bulk of the Ebizo clan’s warriors are ebi’ishi—hardy lobster yokai with natural carapaces as durable as lacquered armour. Their roles range from city guards to infantry soldiers, while elder ebi’ishi serve as elite juggernauts tasked with the defence of zuwai. With experience comes strength and wisdom, an adage that rings particularly true among the ebi’ishi, for they never cease growing. Over time, their shells and claws become increasingly thick and mighty, with elders bearing carapaces so dense they deflect weapons with the ease of waves breaking on rock. However, as their weight and strength increase, their mobility suffers. The ultimate fate of an ebi’ishi is for their carapace to grow so heavy that it crushes the flesh within. To collapse under the weight of one’s shell is seen as an honourable death for an otherwise unconquerable warrior of the Ebizo clan.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Large Fiend (Yokai), Lawful Evil</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 22 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 152 (16d10 + 64)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 10ft., swim 60ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +3</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>22 (+6)</td><td>7 (-2)</td><td>19 (+4)</td><td>9 (-1)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>12 (+1)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Athletics +9</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> cold, poison; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> blindsight 10ft., darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 12</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> Aquan, Common</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 8 (3,900 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The ebi’ishi elder makes two attacks with any combination of Claw and Spear</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Claw.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 19 (2d12 + 6) piercing damage. Instead of dealing damage, the ebi’ishi elder can grapple the target (escape DC 19). Either way, if the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 17 Strength saving throw or drop whatever it’s holding.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Spear.</em></strong> Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d6 + 6) piercing damage.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Ink Spray (Recharge 3-6).</em></strong> The ebi’ishi elder hurls a glob of ink at one creature it can see within 60 feet of itself. The target must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or be blinded until the end of its next turn. While underwater, the ebi’ishi instead expels an ink cloud in a 30-foot radius. The cloud spreads around corners and heavily obscures the area. Each creature other than the ebi’ishi elder that ends its turn there must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw, taking 27 (5d10) poison damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. A strong current disperses the ink cloud, which otherwise disappears at the end of the ebi’ishi elder’s next turn.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Kanibozu" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_KANIBOZU">
		<description>
            <p>The kanibozu are esteemed nobles that form the backbone of the Ebizo society, often acting as teachers, seers, historians, healers, and spies. These yokai have a particular affinity for illusion magic, with many legends told of kanibozu infiltrating isetsu outlooks disguised as roaming mercenaries or masquerading as priests within monasteries, dutifully playing their roles for decades before being caught. In their true form, every kanibozu carries a lantern—a focus through which they channel their magic and an immutable symbol of authority and status. In the haunting darkness and crushing depths of the ocean, the distant, eerie light of a kanibozu is a bolstering force of hope for the Ebizo and a stern warning to its enemies.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Medium Fiend (Yokai), Neutral</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 18 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 95 (10d8 + 50)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 30ft., swim 40ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +3</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>17 (+3)</td><td>11 (+0)</td><td>20 (+5)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>10 (+0)</td><td>18 (+4)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Deception +7, Stealth +3</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> cold, poison; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from non-magical attacks</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 10</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> Aquan, Common</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 5 (1,800 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Lantern Bearer.</em></strong> The kanibozu carries a lantern that sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. It can extinguish or light the lantern as a bonus action. Creatures of the kanibozu’s choice within the lantern’s light gain a 1d4 bonus to attack and damage rolls (included in the kanibozu’s attacks).</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Staff.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +6 plus 1d4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (1d8 + 1d4 + 3) bludgeoning damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Stinging Ray.</em></strong> Ranged Spell Attack: +7 plus 1d4 to hit, range 120 ft., one target. Hit: 22 (3d10 + 1d4 + 3) radiant damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Illusory Form.</em></strong> The kanibozu casts the disguise self spell, using Charisma as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 15).</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Inversion Illusion.</em></strong> The kanibozu attempts to craft an illusion in the mind of a creature it can see within 60 feet of it. The target must make a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the area within 20 feet of the kanibozu’s lantern becomes obscured by pitch darkness for that creature, regardless of other illumination. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of its turn, ending the effect on a success.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Zuwai" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_ZUWAI">
		<description>
            <p>The Ebizo believe that all things belong to the ocean, and the ocean belongs to the zuwai. Matriarchs among the Ebizo, these deep-sea elementalists tower over the rest of the clan, both in stature and magical prowess. Among their kin, zuwai act as chieftains and battlefield commanders, masterminding the flow of combat from afar and rarely engaging personally. However, should the need arise, zuwai are fearsome warriors innately equipped with lethal magic. Their grace in battle is unmatched; the zuwai’s many limbs move with spectacular synchronicity as they channel the element of water through precise movements—an uncanny union of delicate motion and crushing tidal force. In many ways, zuwai are the ocean’s erratic temperament incarnate, at one moment beautiful in tranquillity, the next terrifying in tempestuous rage.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Large Fiend (Yokai), Lawful Evil</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 19 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 178 (17d10 + 85)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 40ft., swim 60ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +4</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>14 (+2)</td><td>20 (+5)</td><td>20 (+5)</td><td>18 (+4)</td><td>11 (+0)</td><td>18 (+4)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Saving Throws</strong> Con +9, Wis +4</li>
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Acrobatics +9, Persuasion +8, Stealth +9</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> cold, poison; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from non-magical attacks</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> charmed, exhaustion, frightened, paralyzed, poisoned, stunned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 10</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> Aquan, Common</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 10 (5,900 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Magical Carapace (3/Day).</em></strong> When the zuwai fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead. If it does so, a layer of its carapace shatters and sheds, and it has a -1 penalty to AC until it finishes a long rest.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The zuwai makes two attacks with any combination of Claw and Tidal Surge.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Claw.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 18 (2d12 + 5) piercing damage, plus 13 (3d8) cold damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Tidal Surge.</em></strong> Ranged Spell Attack: +8 to hit, range 120 ft., one target. Hit: 28 (8d6) bludgeoning damage, and if the target is a creature, the zuwai can move that creature up to 30 feet in a direction of its choice.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Tidal Grasp (Recharge 6).</em></strong> The zuwai conjures three tendrils of undulating water that attempt to ensnare up to three Large or smaller creatures within 60 feet of it. Each target must succeed on a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw or be restrained for 1 minute. While restrained in this way, a creature is also drowning—it cannot breathe, speak, or perform the verbal components of spells. The target, or a creature within 5 feet of it, can use an action to attempt a DC 16 Strength saving throw, ending the effect on it on a success.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Water Wyrm (1/Day).</em></strong> The zuwai casts the water wyrm spell (at 4th level), using Charisma as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 16, +8 to hit with spell attacks).</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Reactions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Drowning Shield.</em></strong> When a creature within 60 feet of the zuwai makes an attack roll, the zuwai can conjure a bubble of water around itself. It gains a +5 bonus to AC until the start of its next turn. If the zuwai is hit with an attack roll while this shield is in place, the bubble bursts, and all other creatures within 15 feet it must succeed on a DC 16 Strength saving throw or take 22 (4d10) bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Hone Karakasa" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_HONE_KARAKASA">
		<description>
            <p>Cavorting with the roaring wind and singing with every crash of thunder, a bundle of torn red cloth held together by a wooden frame dances through a darkened sky. It is a hone karakasa, joyous and unfettered by the rain and gale of a driving tempest. Resembling a torn-up umbrella with its bamboo skeleton exposed, this large and unusual tsukumogami is a sight that sends civilians scarpering indoors—but not to protect themselves from the hone karakasa itself. On days such as these, where the flying yokai is glimpsed in a distant sky, it acts as the harbinger of an oncoming storm. As such, the hone karakasa’s appearance is a useful sign to many Humanoids, albeit rarely a welcome one.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>A Bone to Pick. </strong>Tsukumogami are known to be a class of mischievous, playful yokai; sometimes troublesome, sometimes helpful, but rarely ever outright hostile; the exception is the hone karakasa. An elder tsukumogami whose great lifespan allows it to grow larger and stronger than its younger counterparts, this oversized umbrella is far more aggressive and belligerent than others of its kind. It subsists on a diet almost exclusively consisting of small animals, hunting under the cover of mighty storms, seizing prey spooked from their nests by flashes of lightning and rumbles of thunder. As opportunists, hone karakasa have been known to steal food from Humanoids as well, and eagerly strike up fights with whoever the wind brings them before.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Leader of the Flock. </strong>Because of their age, aggression, and relative strength, whenever tsukumogami gather, a hone karakasa often emerges as the leader of the band. They often fly at the head of a yokai parade, dancing high and free in a proud and beautiful display—their papery wings spread wide, inspiring awe in the gaggle of smaller tsukumogami stumbling in their wake.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Medium Fey (Yokai), Chaotic Neutral</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 14</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 30 (4d8 + 8)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 1ft., fly 40ft..</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +5</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>13 (+1)</td><td>18 (+4)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>7 (-2)</td><td>12 (+1)</td><td>15 (+2)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Acrobatics +6, Stealth +6</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> cold, lightning, thunder</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 30ft., passive Perception 11</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 2 (450 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Flyby.</em></strong> The hone karakasa doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks when it flies out of an enemy’s reach.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Storm Guardian.</em></strong> The hone karakasa can impart a flying speed equal to its own to any creature it is grappling. Such a creature also has resistance to cold, lightning, and thunder damage. The hone karakasa can only grapple one creature in this way at a time.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Windrider.</em></strong> While the hone karakasa is outside in stormy weather conditions, it’s flying speed is doubled.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The hone karakasa makes two Slam attacks.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Slam.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d8 + 4) bludgeoning damage.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Gusting Winds (Recharge 4-6).</em></strong> The hone karakasa emits a mighty rush of wind in a line that is 30 feet long and 10 feet wide, which blasts in a direction of its choice. Each creature in that line must succeed on a DC 12 Strength saving throw or be pushed 15 feet away from the hone karakasa. The blast of wind disperses gas or vapor, and it extinguishes candles, torches, and similar unprotected flames in the area. It causes protected flames, such as those of lanterns, to dance wildly and has a 50 percent chance to extinguish them.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Jorogumo" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_JOROGUMO">
		<description>
            <p>Of all the fiendish yokai that prowl the land, few can match the cunning and ingenuity of the jorogumo: a shapeshifting spider-demon with a humanoid head and torso grotesquely perched atop the abdomen of a giant spider. Horror stories tell of quaint, luxurious roadside inns that seem to pop up out of nowhere, beckoning merchants and travellers alike with the promise of full bellies, soft sheets, and a charming host. Those foolish enough to be ensnared by these promises never return—stolen from their beds, wrapped up in sweet-scented silk, and dragged below the earth to the jorogumo’s lair. Here they are left, desperate and struggling, surrounded by the corpses of others caught by the demon yokai, their muffled screams meritless as they lie trapped in a dark, webbed tomb. Particularly sadistic jorogumo visit their prey, singing soft tales of lost love and fallen heroes, holding them in a tender caress, and revelling in the thrill of their victims’ absolute terror before devouring them utterly.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Living Form. </strong>The jorogumo’s most subtle art is that of shapeshifting, capable of assuming the form of a Humanoid and integrating among its prey. Some jorogumo spend years in plain sight, mimicking the lives and habits of ordinary townsfolk, accruing a kill count in the hundreds over decades of careful slaughter. To some jorogumo, this sickly Humanoid pantomime is as satisfying as the kill itself.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Empty Shell. </strong>The magic of the jorogumo’s form extends beyond mere shapeshifting. They must shed regularly as they grow, and this discarded shell of flesh and webbing holds magic of its own. It is a husk—a mindless, predatory shadow of the true jorogumo. While it possesses no malice, it is still extremely dangerous; jorogumo husks are driven only by a relentless, aching need to be whole once more. They burn with a yearning to consume—to wrap around another as a cocoon of flesh. Victims of jorogumo husks are consumed, enveloped by the ghastly undead and suspended within it. The husk and its slaughtered victim then undergo a metamorphosis, and a new jorogumo is born, able to shapeshift into the likeness of the creature the husk devoured.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Spider Arts. </strong>Jorogumo are consummate artists, exhibiting mastery across various crafts, including carpentry, artifice, song, and dance. Their performances are nothing short of sirenical, drawing in all manner of beings who stand in awe at their beauty and talent, blissfully unaware of the horror that awaits them just below the floorboards of the stage.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Large Fiend (Yokai), Lawful Evil</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 16 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 170 (20d10 + 60)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 40ft., climb 40ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +3</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>18 (+4)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>12 (+1)</td><td>20 (+5)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Saving Throws</strong> Dex +6, Cha +8</li>
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Acrobatics +6, Deception +8, Performance +8, Persuasion +8, Stealth +6</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> necrotic</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> charmed, frightened, poisoned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., tremorsense 30ft., passive Perception 11</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> Abyssal, Common, Sylvan</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 7 (2,900 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Spider Climb.</em></strong> The jorogumo can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Web Walker.</em></strong> While in contact with a web, the jorogumo knows the exact location of any other creature in contact with the same web. The jorogumo also ignores movement restrictions caused by webbing.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Magic Resistance.</em></strong> The jorogumo has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The jorogumo uses its Charm. It then makes two Venom Shot attacks. It can replace one attack with a use of Webweaver.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Venom Shot.</em></strong> Ranged Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, range 30/90 ft., one target. Hit: 20 (3d10 + 4) poison damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Charm.</em></strong> The jorogumo targets one Humanoid it can see within 30 feet of it. If the target can see the jorogumo, the target must succeed on a DC 16 Wisdom saving throw or be charmed for the next 24 hours. The charmed target regards the jorogumo as a delicate innocent to be loved and protected. Although the target isn’t under the jorogumo’s control, it takes the jorogumo’s requests or actions in the most favourable way it can. The first time on a turn the target takes damage, it can repeat this saving throw, ending the effect on a success.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Webweaver.</em></strong> The jorogumo casts the web spell, requiring no spell components, without requiring concentration, and using Charisma as the spellcasting ability (spell save DC 16).</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Venom Channeler (Recharge 5-6).</em></strong> The jorogumo channels a potent poison through its webbing. Each creature within 120 feet of the jorogumo that is in contact with the same web as it must make a DC 16 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 36 (8d8) poison damage and suffers one random condition chosen from the following options until the end of its next turn. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and doesn’t suffer a condition.</li>
                <ol>
                    <li>Blinded</li>
                    <li>Frightened</li>
                    <li>Poisoned</li>
                    <li>Restrained</li>
                </ol>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Shapeshifter.</em></strong> The jorogumo magically polymorphs into a Small or Medium Humanoid. Its statistics and capabilities, other than its size, remain the same. It reverts to its true form if it makes a Venom Shot attack, uses its Webweaver or Venom Channeler actions, or dies.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Jorogumo Husk" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_JOROGUMO_HUSK">
		<description>
            <p>Of all the fiendish yokai that prowl the land, few can match the cunning and ingenuity of the jorogumo: a shapeshifting spider-demon with a humanoid head and torso grotesquely perched atop the abdomen of a giant spider. Horror stories tell of quaint, luxurious roadside inns that seem to pop up out of nowhere, beckoning merchants and travellers alike with the promise of full bellies, soft sheets, and a charming host. Those foolish enough to be ensnared by these promises never return—stolen from their beds, wrapped up in sweet-scented silk, and dragged below the earth to the jorogumo’s lair. Here they are left, desperate and struggling, surrounded by the corpses of others caught by the demon yokai, their muffled screams meritless as they lie trapped in a dark, webbed tomb. Particularly sadistic jorogumo visit their prey, singing soft tales of lost love and fallen heroes, holding them in a tender caress, and revelling in the thrill of their victims’ absolute terror before devouring them utterly.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Living Form. </strong>The jorogumo’s most subtle art is that of shapeshifting, capable of assuming the form of a Humanoid and integrating among its prey. Some jorogumo spend years in plain sight, mimicking the lives and habits of ordinary townsfolk, accruing a kill count in the hundreds over decades of careful slaughter. To some jorogumo, this sickly Humanoid pantomime is as satisfying as the kill itself.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Empty Shell. </strong>The magic of the jorogumo’s form extends beyond mere shapeshifting. They must shed regularly as they grow, and this discarded shell of flesh and webbing holds magic of its own. It is a husk—a mindless, predatory shadow of the true jorogumo. While it possesses no malice, it is still extremely dangerous; jorogumo husks are driven only by a relentless, aching need to be whole once more. They burn with a yearning to consume—to wrap around another as a cocoon of flesh. Victims of jorogumo husks are consumed, enveloped by the ghastly undead and suspended within it. The husk and its slaughtered victim then undergo a metamorphosis, and a new jorogumo is born, able to shapeshift into the likeness of the creature the husk devoured.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Spider Arts. </strong>Jorogumo are consummate artists, exhibiting mastery across various crafts, including carpentry, artifice, song, and dance. Their performances are nothing short of sirenical, drawing in all manner of beings who stand in awe at their beauty and talent, blissfully unaware of the horror that awaits them just below the floorboards of the stage.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Large Undead (Yokai), Chaotic Evil</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 15 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 68 (8d10 + 24)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 30ft., climb 30ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +2</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>16 (+3)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>1 (-5)</td><td>10 (+0)</td><td>1 (-5)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Stealth +5</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> cold, necrotic</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> charmed, exhaustion, frightened, poisoned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 10</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 2 (450 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Aching Emptiness.</em></strong> When the husk kills a Humanoid with its Devour attack, the Humanoid’s corpse is left suspended and encased with webbing inside the husk’s carapace. Over the next 24 hours, the two fuse together, and the husk is reborn as a jorogumo that can take the appearance of the Humanoid it killed with its Shapeshifter action.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Spider Climb.</em></strong> The husk can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Web Walker.</em></strong> While in contact with a web, the husk knows the exact location of any other creature in contact with the same web. The husk also ignores movement restrictions caused by webbing.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The husk makes two attacks with any combination of Bite and Web.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Bite.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (2d6 + 3) piercing damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Web.</em></strong> Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 30/60 ft., one creature. Hit: The target is restrained by webbing. As an action, the restrained target can make a DC 13 Strength check, bursting the webbing on a success. The webbing can also be attacked and destroyed (AC 10; hp 5; vulnerability to fire damage; immunity to bludgeoning, poison, and psychic damage).</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Devour.</em></strong> . Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one restrained creature. Hit: 28 (8d6) necrotic damage, and the target is grappled (escape DC 13).</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Kamaitachi" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_KAMAITACHI">
		<description>
            <p>The skittering click-clack of bladed forelimbs across a courtyard’s stone paving is the telltale indicator of a kamaitachi nearby. As nimble and flighty as mountain winds, these weasel-like yokai dart from shadow to shadow, kicking up whirling eddies of dust and leaves in their wake.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Deadly Scavenger. </strong>Kamaitachi prefer to scavenge food, sneaking close to settlements and pilfering what they can under the cover of darkness. If forced to hunt, they tend to ambush prey, striking swiftly for a surgical, clean kill. Though aggressive and dangerous in battle, kamaitachi are not malicious and rarely strike without reason or provocation.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Reactive Power. </strong>The kamaitachi’s most unusual power is its ability to harness the strength of those it fights. When threatened by a powerful predator, the yokai becomes a devastating flurry of blades, intimidating the foe with its lacerating performance before dashing away as a whirlwind of fur and strikes. The greater the threat, the more deadly the kamaitachi becomes; even the boldest adventurers and mightiest monsters treat kamaitachi with respect.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Small Fey (Yokai), Chaotic Neutral</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 14 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 22 (4d6 + 8)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 40ft., climb 30ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +2</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>5 (-3)</td><td>15 (+2)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>7 (-2)</td><td>13 (+1)</td><td>16 (+3)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Acrobatics +4, Stealth +6</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 11</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 1 (200 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Frenzy.</em></strong> After the kamaitachi makes its second attack roll on a turn, it has advantage on attack rolls until the end of the turn.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The kamaitachi makes a number of Sickle Claw attacks equal to the proficiency bonus of the first creature it attacks on its turn (minimum of two).</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Sickle Claw.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) slashing damage plus 3 (1d6) slashing damage for each other attack the kamaitachi has made this turn.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Dust Devil.</em></strong> The kamaitachi conjures a small vortex of wind, dust, and leaves around itself. Until the start of its next turn, it levitates 4 inches above the ground. While floating in this way, it can move normally, it ignores difficult terrain, and its movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Kappa" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_KAPPA">
		<description>
            <p>A fisherman cautiously drops to his haunches by a sodden riverbank and lays down a curious offering with a shaking hand. It is a bag of fresh cucumbers, each scrubbed and polished to perfection. Moments later, a scaly, webbed hand breaks the surface of the water, and a kappa hauls itself from the depths, its head covered by a smattering of river weeds. It opens the bag and examines the goods carefully. Satisfied, the kappa slings the bag over its back and leaps back into the water, returning with a basket of freshly caught fish for the fisherman moments later. Their trade completed, both fisherman and kappa go their separate ways, each with dinner in hand and a smile on their face.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Candid Friend, Dangerous Foe. </strong>The kappa are wellknown as honorable and trustworthy yokai; they will return a bow to even the most hated adversary before battle and will never willingly break a promise. That said, they are ruthless and dangerous if threatened or insulted. Grasping hands and uncanny strength make the kappa fearsome grapplers, often overpowering prey on land before dragging them into the waters to drown. Defeat at the hands of an angered kappa leads to a clawing, desperate, and painful death.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Crying Over Spilled Water. </strong>Every kappa has a bowl-like indentation on their heads that must be filled with water at all times. Should this water ever dry up or spill, the kappa weakens. To prevent evaporation, most kappa keep their heads covered with water weeds while on land. Should a cunning foe knock a kappa over or trick them into straying too far from a water source, they can gain the upper hand in a battle with the unfortunate yokai.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Small Fey (Yokai), Chaotic Neutral</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 14 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 58 (9d8 + 18)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 30ft., swim 30ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +2</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>16 (+3)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>10 (+0)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>8 (-1)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Athletics +5</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 13</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> Common, Sylvan</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 2 (450 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Amphibious.</em></strong> The kappa can breathe air and water.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Honourable Combatant.</em></strong> If a creature bows to the kappa immediately after rolling initiative, the kappa will bow in return. Both creatures take a -5 penalty to their initiative roll.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Seasoned Wrangler.</em></strong> The kappa’s speed isn’t reduced while dragging a creature it is grappling.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Water Bowl.</em></strong> The kappa takes 4 (1d8) necrotic damage when it is knocked prone, or at the start of its turn if it is upside down. This trait doesn’t trigger while the kappa is underwater.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The kappa makes two Rough-and-Tumble attacks.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Rough-and-Tumble.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6 + 3) bludgeoning damage, plus 2 (1d4) bludgeoning damage if the target is grappled by the kappa.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Death Roll.</em></strong> The kappa rolls and thrashes a creature it is grappling that is submerged in water. The creature must make a DC 13 Strength saving throw, taking 21 (6d6) bludgeoning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful save. Creatures without a swimming speed make this save with disadvantage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Water Magic.</em></strong> The kappa casts the water whip spell, using Wisdom as the spellcasting modifier (save DC 13, +5 to hit with spell attacks). It can use the water in its head as the source of water from which the whip emerges.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Rugged Grapple (Recharge 5-6).</em></strong> The kappa attempts to grapple one creature within 5 feet of it. The kappa has advantage on its ability check.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Kappa Tideweaver" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_KAPPA_TIDEWEAVER">
		<description>
            <p>A fisherman cautiously drops to his haunches by a sodden riverbank and lays down a curious offering with a shaking hand. It is a bag of fresh cucumbers, each scrubbed and polished to perfection. Moments later, a scaly, webbed hand breaks the surface of the water, and a kappa hauls itself from the depths, its head covered by a smattering of river weeds. It opens the bag and examines the goods carefully. Satisfied, the kappa slings the bag over its back and leaps back into the water, returning with a basket of freshly caught fish for the fisherman moments later. Their trade completed, both fisherman and kappa go their separate ways, each with dinner in hand and a smile on their face.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Candid Friend, Dangerous Foe. </strong>The kappa are wellknown as honorable and trustworthy yokai; they will return a bow to even the most hated adversary before battle and will never willingly break a promise. That said, they are ruthless and dangerous if threatened or insulted. Grasping hands and uncanny strength make the kappa fearsome grapplers, often overpowering prey on land before dragging them into the waters to drown. Defeat at the hands of an angered kappa leads to a clawing, desperate, and painful death.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Crying Over Spilled Water. </strong>Every kappa has a bowl-like indentation on their heads that must be filled with water at all times. Should this water ever dry up or spill, the kappa weakens. To prevent evaporation, most kappa keep their heads covered with water weeds while on land. Should a cunning foe knock a kappa over or trick them into straying too far from a water source, they can gain the upper hand in a battle with the unfortunate yokai.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Medium Fey (Yokai), Neutral</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 15 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 117 (18d8 + 36)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 30ft., swim 30ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +2</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>16 (+3)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>10 (+0)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>8 (-1)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Arcana +6, Athletics +5</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 13</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> Common, Sylvan</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 4 (450 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Amphibious.</em></strong> The kappa can breathe air and water.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Honourable Combatant.</em></strong> If a creature bows to the kappa immediately after rolling initiative, the kappa will bow in return. Both creatures take a -5 penalty to their initiative roll.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Water Bowl.</em></strong> The kappa takes 4 (1d8) necrotic damage when it is knocked prone, or at the start of its turn if it is upside down. This trait doesn’t trigger while the kappa is underwater.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Rough-and-Tumble.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6 + 3) bludgeoning damage, or 10 (2d6 + 3) bludgeoning damage if the target is grappled by the kappa or restrained by its water wyrm.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Death Roll.</em></strong> The kappa rolls and thrashes a creature it is grappling that is submerged in water. The creature must make a DC 13 Strength saving throw, taking 21 (6d6) bludgeoning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. If the creature doesn’t have a swimming speed, it has disadvantage on this saving throw.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Tideweaver (1/Day).</em></strong> The kappa casts the water wyrm spell (save DC 14, +6 to hit with spell attacks). The kappa has advantage on Constitution saving throws to maintain its concentration on the spell.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Water Bubble.</em></strong> The kappa conjures a bubble of living water. The bubble wraps moves with the kappa, enveloping it and any creature the kappa grapples. Creatures enveloped by the water bubble have a +2 bonus to AC. If a creature enveloped by the water bubble cannot breathe in water, it also cannot speak, cannot perform the verbal components of spells, and has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks. The bubble lasts for 1 minute, or until the kappa falls unconscious.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Rugged Grapple (Recharge 5-6).</em></strong> The kappa attempts to grapple one creature within 5 feet of it. The kappa has advantage on its ability check.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Kasha" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_KASHA">
		<description>
            <p class = "flavour">They’re cruel, malevolent, and gleefully evil... So, pretty much your standard cat. —Ryoko</p>
            <p>Under the falling rain, a solemn funeral procession winds through a weary town. Two priests lead the parade, each bearing a pair of ceremonial cymbals. Each heavy step forward is met with a gentle knell—the ancient, ritual pulse of clashing bronze to ward off any evil spirit who might disrupt the tragic vigil. At such an event, no yokai is more feared than the ruthless kasha, a flaming feline monster with a penchant for stealing and devouring the dead. Unbeknownst to the grieving procession, in the deep shadows cast by a slowly fading sun, a steady hiss of steam whispers. It is the sound of rainwater boiling on contact with flame, as a ravenous yokai stalks its next meal.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Hell's Harvester. </strong>. Of all the yokai known, there are few reviled like the kasha. Their preferred source of food is carrion, but unlike other scavengers that happily feast on rotting flesh, kasha prefer their meals fresh—and Humanoid. More grotesque still, kasha have a sadistic love for dead things, often taking fresh corpses back to their lairs to skin, carve, and preserve.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Flaming Cart. </strong> While more than willing to stay patient and cunning while hunting, when threatened, a kasha’s body becomes wreathed in flames. Once discovered, it acts with extreme aggression—terrifying its victims with its flaming form and dashing around the battlefield. Such is their agility in this state that they are often likened to a flaming wagon barreling down a desolate track, unimpeded and at full speed.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Medium Fiend (Yokai), Chaotic Evil</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 12 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 30 (4d8 + 12)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 40ft., climb 30ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +2</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>17 (+3)</td><td>12 (+1)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>10 (+0)</td><td>9 (-1)</td><td>16 (+3)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Intimidation +5, Stealth +3</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> fire</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 120ft., passive Perception 9</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> Infernal</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 1 (200 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Flaming Feline.</em></strong> The first time on a turn that a creature touches the kasha or hits it with a melee attack while within 5 feet of it, that creature takes 2 (1d4) fire damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Steam Eruption.</em></strong> The first time on a turn the kasha comes into contact with a body of water, or a gallon of water is splashed on it, the flames on its body are extinguished and burst into a cloud of steam. The kasha takes 3 (1d6) cold damage, it loses its Flaming Feline trait, and the steam creates a 10-foot-radius sphere of white vapour centred on the kasha’s space, heavily obscuring the area. These changes last until the end of its next turn, at which time its body becomes wreathed in flames again.</li>
            </ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The kasha makes one Bite attack and one Claws attack.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Bite.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6 + 3) piercing damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Claws.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (2d4 + 3) slashing damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Twin-Tail Slam.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 12 (2d8 + 3) bludgeoning damage.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Fiery Dread (Recharge 6).</em></strong> The kasha erupts in flames. Each creature within 30 feet of the kasha that can see it must succeed on a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of the kasha for 1 minute, or until its flames are extinguished. A creature can repeat this saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature’s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the kasha’s Fiery Dread for the next 24 hours.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Stone Komainu" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_STONE_KOMAINU">
		<description>
            <p>With the agility of a hunting hound and the ferocious maw of a lion, these stone-skinned yokai are the dormant guardians of shrines and holy places. If a long-abandoned temple hasn’t yet been plundered of its treasure, these ever-vigilant protectors are the likely explanation; should a would-be thief defile a site guarded by komainu, the petrified statues spring to life, their spectral manes igniting with a rumble that rings deep into the ancient stones of the temple. Screams of pain usually follow.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Artisanal Guardians. </strong>In the folktales of many races, komainu have simply “always been”—where a shrine exists, komainu are there to guard it. Some tales, shared among only the most ancient communities, tell of foreboding yokai spirits, attracted to areas of intense devotion, finding a home in these painstakingly carved statues. Channelling the magic of the yokai soul they house, these stoic Fey elicit a variety of magical effects based on the material from which they are crafted. Though typically made of stone or jade, legend tells of mighty komainu cast from precious metals like adamantine and gold who keep watch over treasure beyond imagination.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>The Beginning and the End. </strong>Komainu are commonly found in pairs, with each creature’s maw displaying one of two syllables: “Un” or “Ah”. These sounds represent the beginning and end of all things, respectively. Komainu displaying a snarling, closed-mouthed “Un” might manifest powers of healing, growth, and light, while those showing a roaring, open-mouthed “Ah” can unleash devastating waves of necrotic energy or banish interlopers to a distant plane of existence.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Medium Fey (Yokai), Lawful Good</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 16 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 30 (4d8 + 12)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 40ft., climb 30ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +2</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>17 (+3)</td><td>15 (+2)</td><td>17 (+3)</td><td>7 (-2)</td><td>15 (+2)</td><td>13 (+1)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Athletics +5, Acrobatics +4, Stealth +6</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> necrotic, poison</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> charmed, exhaustion, frightened, petrified</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 12</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 2 (450 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Radiant Mane.</em></strong> Any creature grappling the komainu takes 5 (2d4) radiant damage at the start of its turn, and the komainu’s weapon attacks count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistances and immunity to nonmagical attacks.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Statue Form.</em></strong> While the komainu’s Radiant Mane is not active (see Fortification of Stone) and it remains motionless, it is indistinguishable from an ordinary statue.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The komainu makes one Claw attack and one Divine Mace attack.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Claw.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (2d4 + 3) slashing damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Divine Mace.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6 + 3) bludgeoning damage plus 3 (1d6) radiant damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Beginning and End.</em></strong> The komainu switches between its “Un” and “Ah” forms.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Manifestation (Recharge 6).</em></strong> The komainu manifests one of the following effects.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Duskbringer (Ah Form Only).</em></strong> The komainu exhales withering energy in a 15-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw, taking 18 (4d8) necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Shrineward (Un Form Only).</em></strong> The komainu conjures a nonmagical wall of stone at a point it chooses with 60 feet of it, composed of three contiguous 10-foot-by-10-foot panels. If the wall cuts through a creature’s space when it appears, the creature must succeed on a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw or take 9 (2d8) bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone in the nearest unoccupied space of the komainu’s choice. Each panel has AC 15 and 30 hit points. A panel crumbles to dust if it is reduced to 0 hit points or after 1 minute.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Fortification of Stone.</em></strong> The komainu’s spirit retreats back into its body. It loses its Radiant Mane trait, can’t use or recharge its Manifestation action, has its speed reduced by 10 feet, and gains resistance to bludgeoning, slashing, and piercing damage. This effect lasts until the komainu ends it as a bonus action, reigniting its Radiant Mane.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Jade Komainu" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_JADE_KOMAINU">
		<description>
            <p>With the agility of a hunting hound and the ferocious maw of a lion, these stone-skinned yokai are the dormant guardians of shrines and holy places. If a long-abandoned temple hasn’t yet been plundered of its treasure, these ever-vigilant protectors are the likely explanation; should a would-be thief defile a site guarded by komainu, the petrified statues spring to life, their spectral manes igniting with a rumble that rings deep into the ancient stones of the temple. Screams of pain usually follow.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Artisanal Guardians. </strong>In the folktales of many races, komainu have simply “always been”—where a shrine exists, komainu are there to guard it. Some tales, shared among only the most ancient communities, tell of foreboding yokai spirits, attracted to areas of intense devotion, finding a home in these painstakingly carved statues. Channelling the magic of the yokai soul they house, these stoic Fey elicit a variety of magical effects based on the material from which they are crafted. Though typically made of stone or jade, legend tells of mighty komainu cast from precious metals like adamantine and gold who keep watch over treasure beyond imagination.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>The Beginning and the End. </strong>Komainu are commonly found in pairs, with each creature’s maw displaying one of two syllables: “Un” or “Ah”. These sounds represent the beginning and end of all things, respectively. Komainu displaying a snarling, closed-mouthed “Un” might manifest powers of healing, growth, and light, while those showing a roaring, open-mouthed “Ah” can unleash devastating waves of necrotic energy or banish interlopers to a distant plane of existence.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Large Fey (Yokai), Lawful Good</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 16 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 52 (5d10 + 25)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 40ft., climb 30ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +2</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>18 (+4)</td><td>15 (+2)</td><td>20 (+5)</td><td>7 (-2)</td><td>17 (+3)</td><td>13 (+1)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Athletics +6, Acrobatics +4, Stealth +6</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> necrotic, poisonn; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> charmed, exhaustion, frightened, petrified</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 12</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 4 (1,100 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Radiant Mane.</em></strong> Any creature grappling the komainu takes 11 (2d10) radiant damage at the start of its turn, and the komainu’s weapon attacks count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistances and immunity to nonmagical attacks.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Statue Form.</em></strong> While the komainu’s Radiant Mane is not active (see Fortification of Gemstone) and it remains motionless, it is indistinguishable from an ordinary statue.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The komainu makes one Claw attack, one Bite attack, and one Divine Orb attack.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Claw.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d10 + 4) slashing damage.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Bite.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (1d12 + 4) bludgeoning damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Divine Orb.</em></strong> Ranged Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, range 120 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d10 + 4) bludgeoning damage plus 3 (1d6) radiant damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Beginning and End.</em></strong> The komainu switches between its “Un” and “Ah” forms.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Manifestation (Recharge 6).</em></strong> The komainu manifests one of the following effects.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Dawnbringer (Ah Form Only).</em></strong> The komainu exhales brilliant, radiant energy in a 30-foot cone. Each creature of the komainu’s choice in that area gains 18 (4d8) temporary hit points.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Banishment (Un Form Only).</em></strong> The komainu exhales astral energy in a 30-foot cone. Roll 12d6; the total is how many hit points of creatures this spell can affect. Creatures in the area are affected in ascending order of their current hit points. Subtract each creature’s hit points from the total before moving on to the creature with the next lowest hit points. A creature’s hit points must be equal to or less than the remaining total for that creature to be affected. An affected creature is teleported to a random location 1d6 miles away. If a creature can’t be teleported, it is sent to a harmless demiplane; while there, the target is incapacitated.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Fortification of Gemstone.</em></strong> The komainu’s spirit retreats back into its body. It loses its Radiant Mane trait, can’t use or recharge its Manifestation action, has its speed reduced by 10 feet, gains resistance to all damage dealt by spells, and has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects. This effect lasts until the komainu ends it as a bonus action, reigniting its mane.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Korori" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_KORORI">
		<description>
            <p>There exists a yokai whose deadliness is deceptive, whose appearance does not reflect the devastation it leaves in its tread. Long-limbed and tiger-striped, the korōri is a docile-looking creature most commonly found hiding inside tunnels and caves, scuttling away frantically at signs of danger. Despite its cowardice and unassuming presence, however, the korōri is deadly, producing a vicious poison that will lay an entire village to waste if allowed to settle.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Patient Predator. </strong>The korōri hunts by finding a secluded hiding place and lying in wait, curling up into a ball while opening stripe-like vents across its body. From these vents, a lethal, poisonous fume seeps into the area around it. The poison is odourless, almost impossible to detect until the sickness sets in. Some say the korōri reeks of death and decay, but this is inaccurate. The odour of rot that follows its arrival is the stench of living creatures around the korōri that fall prey to its deadly miasma. Only after it detects the scent of rotting flesh does the korōri emerge from its hiding place to feed.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Bringer of Illness. </strong>There is nary a creature more widely feared than this innocuous yokai. While kaiju can destroy cities in mere minutes, there is no Monstrosity, Fiend, or Fey that can lay waste to a populace in such a subtle and silent manner as the korōri. Its poison twists the mind and senses, inciting harrowing hallucinations and excruciating anguish before death, sparing none, even creatures typically immune to venoms and toxicants. The korōri is considered a harbinger of pestilence, a demon of plague and ruin, and a herald of death and rot by cultures from all corners of the realm. A single korōri footprint found on the outskirts of a town is grounds enough for the whole settlement to evacuate immediately.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Large Fiend (Yokai), Unaligned</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 17 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 152 (16d10 + 64)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 40ft., climb 20ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +3</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>18 (+4)</td><td>20 (+5)</td><td>19 (+4)</td><td>9 (-1)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>5 (-3)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Stealth +8</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> poisoned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 8 (3,900 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Hallucinogenic Poison.</em></strong> A creature poisoned by the korōri must make a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw at the start of each of its turns. On a failed save, it becomes frightened of all other creatures until the start of its next turn and must use its action that turn to make one attack against the closest creature it can see within 30 feet of it, believing it to be a terrifying foe. If no creature is visible within 30 feet, it falls prone.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Harrowing Stench.</em></strong> A creature that starts its turn within 20 feet of the korōri takes 9 (2d8) poison damage. Creatures within 20 feet of the korōri have disadvantage on saving throws to avoid or end the poisoned condition.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Magical Toxin.</em></strong> Korōri’s attacks and effects that deal poison damage ignore poison resistance.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The korōri makes two attacks with any combination of Bite and Venom Shot.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Bite.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d6 + 4) piercing damage plus 7 (2d6) poison damage, and the target must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or be poisoned for 1 minute. A poisoned creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the poisoned condition on a success.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Venom Shot.</em></strong> Ranged Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (3d6) poison damage, and the target must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or fall prone and be poisoned for 1 minute. A poisoned creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the poisoned condition on a success.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Pestilent Burst.</em></strong> The korōri releases a sickening burst of poison. Each creature within 30 feet of the korōri must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw, taking 42 (12d6) poison damage and becoming poisoned for 1 minute on a failed save, or taking half as much damage and not becoming poisoned on a successful one. A poisoned creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the poisoned condition on a success.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Narigama" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_NARIGAMA">
		<description>
            <p>Tsukumogami, the feeble, mischievous spirits that find homes possessing worn out objects, are a common sight across the realms, and usually regarded as irritating at best. However, there is one exception—the narigama, a benevolent tsukumogami known for inhabiting well-used and well-loved iron kettles. Appearing as a fuzzy quadrupedal creature with a kettle as its head, the whimsical appearance and character of the narigama, its docile nature, and its valuable ability to predict the future, has endeared it to many folk across the realms.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Spilling the Tea. </strong>Despite a humble appearance, narigama are exceptionally sensitive to their environments and are able to sense minor changes in temperature and air pressure, detect nearly indistinguishable vibrations, and identify distant noises even the keenest Humanoids would be unable to detect. Priests and sailors often teach their narigama pets to make various clicks and whistles to signal information without speech. As a result, they can be trained to reliably predict almost anything, from coming storms to volcanic eruptions, from animal migrations to bandit incursions.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Boiling Hot. </strong>Narigama living in shrines, shipyards, and boats often lead a carefree, spoiled life—their caretakers offering them everything they desire in return for their predictions of the future. However, like most yokai, these fuzzy critters can still pose a threat if they feel threatened. If pressed, a narigama will raise its hackles, give a loud, ear-piercing whistle, and spew a stream of boiling water at its assailant from its kettle head.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Small Fey (Yokai), Lawful Good</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 14 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 27 (5d6 + 10)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 20ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +2</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>7 (-2)</td><td>15 (+2)</td><td>15 (+2)</td><td>9 (-1)</td><td>20 (+5)</td><td>12 (+1)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Insight +9, Perception +9</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> blindsight 60ft., tremorsense 120ft., passive Perception 19</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 1 (200 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Saw It Coming.</em></strong> At the start of its turn, the narigama can focus on one creature it can see if the narigama isn’t incapacitated, analysing every nigh-imperceptible movement and behaviour. Until the start of its next turn, the narigama has advantage on attack rolls against the target, and the target has disadvantage on attack rolls against the narigama.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Scald.</em></strong> Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 30/90 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (2d6 + 2) fire damage.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Reactions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Screaching Whistle.</em></strong> When a creature the narigama is focused on takes an action that forces one or more creatures to make a saving throw, the narigama can let loose a piercing whistle of warning. Any of those creatures that are within 60 feet of the narigama who can hear it make that saving throw with advantage.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Nueko" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_NUEKO">
		<description>
            <p>An eerie, whistling call, like that of a white thrush, is a warning that man, beast, and yokai alike have long learned to fear. It is the call of the nue, a chimeric yokai with the skull of a monkey, the body of a tiger, and a tail that morphs into a venomous serpent. Rumoured to be the first true yokai, it is an ancient sovereign of beasts and an omen of disaster and dread. Sowing chaos wherever it roams, the nue’s ferocity and unpredictable magic represent the last remnant of a forgotten, untamed world.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Nue's Curse. </strong>The nue is notorious for its disaster field—a chaotic, magical aura that inflicts misfortune upon all within its proximity. This power is intertwined with the nue’s mythology, with many stories reciting how its appearance coincided with great tragedy and cataclysm. Some folktales speak of the nue’s curse targeting specific individuals, rendering great warriors and emperors alike helplessly sick for nights on end until either they or the nue are killed.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Nueko. </strong>Nue have litters of three to five young every century, and the birth of these young, called nueko, are significant spiritual moments. While carrying neuko, mother nue are dangerously aggressive and powerful, their disaster fields growing so potent that they disrupt the weather, generating thick, black clouds that plunge acres of land into perpetual darkness and misfortune. Nueko are highly valued by spellcasters, their gentler nature, charming appearance, and innate intelligence making them prized familiars. Unlike the nue, who’s chimeric body serves a singular, lethal purpose, a neuko’s head and tail are independent, often play-fighting with one another and competing for food. Only after a nueko grows into a nue across the first decade of its life do its simian head and serpent tail synchronise into a single mind.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Tiny Fey (Yokai), Chaotic Neutral</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 12</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 18 (4d4 + 8)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 30ft., climb 30ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +2</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>7 (-2)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>15 (+2)</td><td>7 (-2)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>12 (+1)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Stealth +4</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> poisoned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 30ft., passive Perception 13</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 1/2 (100 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Bite.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) piercing damage plus 2 (1d4) poison damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Tail.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4 + 2) piercing damage, and if the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 12 Constitution saving throw or be poisoned until the end of its next turn.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Growl (Recharge 6).</em></strong> The nueko growls affectionately. Creatures within 10 feet of it must succeed on a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or be charmed for 1 minute.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Nue" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_NUE">
		<description>
            <p>An eerie, whistling call, like that of a white thrush, is a warning that man, beast, and yokai alike have long learned to fear. It is the call of the nue, a chimeric yokai with the skull of a monkey, the body of a tiger, and a tail that morphs into a venomous serpent. Rumoured to be the first true yokai, it is an ancient sovereign of beasts and an omen of disaster and dread. Sowing chaos wherever it roams, the nue’s ferocity and unpredictable magic represent the last remnant of a forgotten, untamed world.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Nue's Curse. </strong>The nue is notorious for its disaster field—a chaotic, magical aura that inflicts misfortune upon all within its proximity. This power is intertwined with the nue’s mythology, with many stories reciting how its appearance coincided with great tragedy and cataclysm. Some folktales speak of the nue’s curse targeting specific individuals, rendering great warriors and emperors alike helplessly sick for nights on end until either they or the nue are killed.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Nueko. </strong>Nue have litters of three to five young every century, and the birth of these young, called nueko, are significant spiritual moments. While carrying neuko, mother nue are dangerously aggressive and powerful, their disaster fields growing so potent that they disrupt the weather, generating thick, black clouds that plunge acres of land into perpetual darkness and misfortune. Nueko are highly valued by spellcasters, their gentler nature, charming appearance, and innate intelligence making them prized familiars. Unlike the nue, who’s chimeric body serves a singular, lethal purpose, a neuko’s head and tail are independent, often play-fighting with one another and competing for food. Only after a nueko grows into a nue across the first decade of its life do its simian head and serpent tail synchronise into a single mind.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Large Fey (Yokai), Chaotic Neutral</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 17 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 51 (6d10 + 18)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 40ft., climb 40ft., fly 30ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +3</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>19 (+4)</td><td>18 (+4)</td><td>17 (+3)</td><td>7 (-2)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>12 (+1)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Perception +7, Stealth +6</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> poisoned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 120ft., passive Perception 17</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> telepathy 120ft. (Beasts only)</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 4 (1,100 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Disaster Field.</em></strong> Other creatures within 10 feet of the nue must roll a d6 and subtract the number rolled from their ability checks and saving throws.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The nue makes one Bite attack, one Claw attack, and one Tail attack.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Bite.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d8 + 4) piercing damage plus 3 (1d6) poison damage. If the nue’s attack roll exceeds the target’s AC by 5 or more, the target is also poisoned until the end of its next turn.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Claw.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) slashing damage.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Tail.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d4 + 4) piercing damage. If the target is poisoned, it takes an extra 16 (3d10) poison damage.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Beast Sovereign.</em></strong> The nue casts command, requiring no spell components and using Wisdom as the spellcasting ability (save DC 13). It must target a Beast, issuing the command telepathically.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Whistling Howl (Recharge 6).</em></strong> The nue lets out a howl. Each friendly creature within 30 feet of it that can hear the howl gains advantage on saving throws against the frightened condition for 1 minute. Each other creature within 30 feet of it that can hear the howl must succeed on a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened for 1 minute. A frightened creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Ancient Nue" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_ANCIENT_NUE">
		<description>
            <p>An eerie, whistling call, like that of a white thrush, is a warning that man, beast, and yokai alike have long learned to fear. It is the call of the nue, a chimeric yokai with the skull of a monkey, the body of a tiger, and a tail that morphs into a venomous serpent. Rumoured to be the first true yokai, it is an ancient sovereign of beasts and an omen of disaster and dread. Sowing chaos wherever it roams, the nue’s ferocity and unpredictable magic represent the last remnant of a forgotten, untamed world.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Nue's Curse. </strong>The nue is notorious for its disaster field—a chaotic, magical aura that inflicts misfortune upon all within its proximity. This power is intertwined with the nue’s mythology, with many stories reciting how its appearance coincided with great tragedy and cataclysm. Some folktales speak of the nue’s curse targeting specific individuals, rendering great warriors and emperors alike helplessly sick for nights on end until either they or the nue are killed.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Nueko. </strong>Nue have litters of three to five young every century, and the birth of these young, called nueko, are significant spiritual moments. While carrying neuko, mother nue are dangerously aggressive and powerful, their disaster fields growing so potent that they disrupt the weather, generating thick, black clouds that plunge acres of land into perpetual darkness and misfortune. Nueko are highly valued by spellcasters, their gentler nature, charming appearance, and innate intelligence making them prized familiars. Unlike the nue, who’s chimeric body serves a singular, lethal purpose, a neuko’s head and tail are independent, often play-fighting with one another and competing for food. Only after a nueko grows into a nue across the first decade of its life do its simian head and serpent tail synchronise into a single mind.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Large Fey (Yokai), Chaotic Neutral</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 18 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 189 (18d10 + 90)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 60ft., climb 60ft., fly 40ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +4</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>22 (+6)</td><td>20 (+5)</td><td>21 (+5)</td><td>7 (-2)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>14 (+2)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Perception +11, Stealth +9</li>
                <li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> poisoned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 120ft., passive Perception 21</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> telepathy 120ft. (Beasts only)</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 10 (5,900 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Disaster Field.</em></strong> Other creatures within 10 feet of the nue must roll a d10 and subtract the number rolled from their ability checks and saving throws.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Nue's Curse.</em></strong> A creature hit by three of the nue’s attacks in on turn must make a DC 15 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the target is cursed—its creature type becomes Beast, its Intelligence and Charisma scores fall to 5 if they weren’t already lower, and it can’t cast spells or speak. The creature can still identify friends and foes, attack, and use magic items. This curse lasts until the creature finishes a short or long rest, or until the nue choses to lift the curse (no action required) or dies.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The nue makes one Bite attack, one Claw attack, and one Tail attack. It can replace one of these attacks with a use of Beast Sovereign.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Bite.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 19 (3d8 + 6) piercing damage plus 7 (2d6) poison damage. If the nue’s attack roll exceeds the target’s AC by 5 or more, the target is also poisoned until the end of its next turn.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Claw.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 16 (3d6 + 6) slashing damage.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Tail.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d4 + 6) piercing damage. If the target is poisoned, it takes an extra 33 (6d10) poison damage.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Beast Sovereign (3/Day).</em></strong> The nue issues a telepathic command to up to three Beasts it can see within 60 feet of itself. Each target must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or be forced to use its action on its next turn to attack one creature of the nue’s choice.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Bonus Actions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Whistling Howl (Recharge 5-6).</em></strong> The nue lets out a howl. Each friendly creature within 60 feet of it that can hear the howl gains advantage on saving throws against the frightened condition for 1 minute. Each other creature within 60 feet of it that can hear the howl must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened for 1 minute. A creature that fails this saving throw by 5 or more and is frightened is also paralyzed until the start of its next turn. A frightened creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Omukade Spawn" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_OMUKADE_SPAWN">
		<description>
            <p>In the depths of a green dragon’s lair, a group of adventurers stands paralysed in awe. Before them, the broken corpse of their draconic quarry lies lifeless, its rib cage crushed, its neck broken, and its body surrounded by mysterious, translucent eggs. As if in answer to their bewilderment, a chilling hiss reverberates from the darkness of the cavern. Chitinous scale by colossal, chitinous scale, an ōmukade unfurls its segmented, obsidian form, rising up over the tarnished metal trinkets of the late dragon’s horde. It looms over the trespassers with mandibles bared—mandibles stained green with the crimson ichor of a butchered dragon.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Eater of Dragons. </strong>Many myths and folktales speak of dragons as apex predators: fearless masters of their domain, unmatched by any. These myths and folktales are wrong. The ōmukade are mighty, insectoid yokai who not only hold power comparable to dragons but harbour an insatiable desire to feast on draconic flesh. It is rumoured that the ōmukade were created by gods to balance the ego of dragonkind: a nightmare to remind them of their fragile mortality. Although their origin is shrouded in myth, the hatred of dragons is real and innate to all ōmukade—adults relentlessly seek draconic creatures to devour, laying eggs in a defeated dragon’s nest for their spawn to devour its wyrmlings.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Anti-Draconic Measures. </strong>An ōmukade’s prowess against dragons doesn’t stem from sheer audacity and strength; its very body is designed to withstand and thrive in the face of everything a dragon can unleash. With chitinous armour able to absorb elemental energy and a mighty, constricting body to grapple prey and prevent flight, the ōmukade isan arsenal of anti-dragon attributes, putting even the mostrenowned dragon slayers to shame.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Medium Fey (Yokai), Chaotic Neutral</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 16 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 58 (9d8 + 18)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 30ft., climb 30ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +2</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>17 (+3)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>5 (-3)</td><td>10 (+0)</td><td>8 (-1)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Saving Throws</strong> Dex +5, Con +4</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 10</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 3 (700 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Reactive Growth.</em></strong> When the ōmukade spawn takes acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage, its size increases by one category if there is room (to a maximum of Huge). Each time this occurs, its weight is multiplied by eight, the reach of its Raptorial Stab attack increases by 5 feet, and its weapon attacks deal an extra 1d8 damage. This trait then can’t trigger again until the start of the ōmukade spawn’s next turn. When the ōmukade spawn finishes a long rest, it returns to its normal size and these benefits end.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Crusher.</em></strong> A creature that starts its turn grappled by the ōmukade spawn takes 3 bludgeoning damage.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The ōmukade spawn makes two Raptorial Stab attacks.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Raptorial Stab.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d8 + 3) piercing damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Constrict.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature smaller than the ōmukade spawn. Hit: 14 (2d10 + 3) bludgeoning damage and the target is grappled (escape DC 13) if the ōmukade isn’t already constricting a creature. The target is restrained until this grapple ends.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name = "Omukade" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_OMUKADE">
		<description>
            <p>In the depths of a green dragon’s lair, a group of adventurers stands paralysed in awe. Before them, the broken corpse of their draconic quarry lies lifeless, its rib cage crushed, its neck broken, and its body surrounded by mysterious, translucent eggs. As if in answer to their bewilderment, a chilling hiss reverberates from the darkness of the cavern. Chitinous scale by colossal, chitinous scale, an ōmukade unfurls its segmented, obsidian form, rising up over the tarnished metal trinkets of the late dragon’s horde. It looms over the trespassers with mandibles bared—mandibles stained green with the crimson ichor of a butchered dragon.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Eater of Dragons. </strong>Many myths and folktales speak of dragons as apex predators: fearless masters of their domain, unmatched by any. These myths and folktales are wrong. The ōmukade are mighty, insectoid yokai who not only hold power comparable to dragons but harbour an insatiable desire to feast on draconic flesh. It is rumoured that the ōmukade were created by gods to balance the ego of dragonkind: a nightmare to remind them of their fragile mortality. Although their origin is shrouded in myth, the hatred of dragons is real and innate to all ōmukade—adults relentlessly seek draconic creatures to devour, laying eggs in a defeated dragon’s nest for their spawn to devour its wyrmlings.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Anti-Draconic Measures. </strong>An ōmukade’s prowess against dragons doesn’t stem from sheer audacity and strength; its very body is designed to withstand and thrive in the face of everything a dragon can unleash. With chitinous armour able to absorb elemental energy and a mighty, constricting body to grapple prey and prevent flight, the ōmukade isan arsenal of anti-dragon attributes, putting even the mostrenowned dragon slayers to shame.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Huge Fey (Yokai), Chaotic Neutral</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 21 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 187 (15d12 + 90)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 50ft., burrow 30ft., climb 50ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +5</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>24 (+7)</td><td>18 (+4)</td><td>22 (+6)</td><td>5 (-3)</td><td>10 (+0)</td><td>8 (-1)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Saving Throws</strong> Dex +9, Con +11</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 120ft., tremorsense 60ft., passive Perception 10</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> —</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 15 (13,000 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Reactive Growth.</em></strong> When the ōmukade takes acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage, its size increases by one category if there is room (to a maximum of Gargantuan). Each time this occurs, its weight is multiplied by eight, the reach of its Raptorial Stab attack increases by 5 feet, and its weapon attacks deal an extra 1d8 damage. This trait then can’t trigger again until the start of the ōmukade’s next turn. When the ōmukade finishes a long rest, it returns to its normal size and these benefits end.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Crusher.</em></strong> . A creature that starts its turn grappled by the ōmukade takes 15 bludgeoning damage.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The ōmukade makes one Bite or Swallow attack and two Raptorial Stab attacks.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Bite.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 25 (4d8 + 7) piercing damage. If the target is a creature smaller than the ōmukade, it is grappled (escape DC 20). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained and the ōmukade can’t use its Bite attack on another target.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Constrict.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature smaller than the ōmukade. Hit: 62 (10d10 + 7) bludgeoning damage and the target is grappled (escape DC 20). The target is also restrained until this grapple ends.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Raptorial Stab.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 20 (3d8 + 7) piercing damage.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Swallow.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 10 ft., one creature two or more sizes smaller than it that is grappled by the ōmukade. Hit: 25 (4d8 + 7) piercing damage. The creature is also swallowed, and the grapple ends. The swallowed creature is blinded and restrained, it has total cover against attacks and other effects outside the ōmukade, and it takes 28 (8d6) acid damage at the start of each of the ōmukade’s turns.</li>
                <li class = "indent">If the ōmukade takes 30 damage or more on a single turn from a creature inside it, the ōmukade must succeed on a DC 26 Constitution saving throw at the end of that turn or regurgitate all swallowed creatures, which fall prone in a space within 10 feet of it. If the ōmukade dies, a swallowed creature is no longer restrained by it and can escape from the corpse by using 15 feet of movement, exiting prone.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>


	<element name = "Aspect of Ashura" type = "Information" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_INFORMATION_ASPECT_OF_ASHURA">
		<description>
            <p>A favoured subject among poets and thespians across the realms is the tale of Ashura: the three-faced, six-armed demon god of destruction cast down from the heavens by the deities he offended. While the legend of Ashura might end there, his legacy and demonic power endure. Stories shared in hushed, fireside whispers tell of mighty Fiends that befoul the land—creatures echoing the form and power of the defeated demon god. On a path fueled by zealous passion and hate-driven vengeance, they cleave down everything in their way. The original Ashura may be gone, but the aspects of Ashura carry his legacy into the mortal world.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Fragment of Fury. </strong>Aeons ago, upon his defeat, Ashura was broken and scattered to different parts of the world, his power contained and fragmented. Over the centuries, however, like the creeping rust that shatters iron chains, time has weakened these seals, and aspects of Ashura have manifested across the realms. While a mere echo of the true Ashura, these creatures are deadly and cunning, inheriting fearsome magic, deadly battle prowess, and a burning wrath.</p>
            <p class = "indent"><strong>Blood and Lust. </strong>Similar to the original Ashura, the aspects are creatures whose body and mind are set ablaze by the most intense emotions one could feel. Happiness is experienced as nothing less than dizzying ecstasy, anger as nothing less than blinding rage. When met in battle, there is no hope of mercy, surrender, or compromise, and only death can stop them.</p>
            <p></p>
			<p style = "margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Large Fiend (Yokai), Chaotic Evil</em></p>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 17 (natural armour)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> 157 (15d10 + 75)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 50ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Proficiency Bonus</strong> +5</li>
			</ul>
			<table style = "text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>24 (+7)</td><td>20 (+5)</td><td>20 (+5)</td><td>18 (+4)</td><td>9 (-1)</td><td>10 (+0)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong>Saving Throws</strong> Dex +10, Wis +4, Cha +5</li>
				<li><strong>Skills</strong> Arcana +7, Athletics +17, Perception +9</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances</strong> cold, fire; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from non-magical attacks</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> charmed, exhaustion, frightened, paralyzed, poisoned, stunned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 19</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> Abyssal, Common, telepathy 120ft.</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge</strong> 13 (10,000 XP)</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Critical Wound.</em></strong> When the aspect hits a creature with six or more attack rolls on a single turn, that creature’s hit point maximum is reduced by 11 (1d8 + 7). This reduction can’t be undone by any means short of a wish spell.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Reckless.</em></strong> At the start of its turn, the aspect can gain advantage on all melee weapon attack rolls until the start of its next turn, but attack rolls against it have advantage until then.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Three Heads.</em></strong> The aspect can take up to three reactions per round, but only one per turn. It can’t use the same reaction option more than once each round.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Legendary Resistance (3/Day).</em></strong> If the aspect fails a saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class = "unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> The aspect makes six Longsword attacks.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Bite.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (1d6 + 7) piercing damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Longsword.</em></strong> Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (1d8 + 7) slashing damage.</li>
                <p></p>
				<li><strong><em>Ashura's Grasp.</em></strong> The aspect lets loose a burst of grasping conjuration magic, forcing one creature it can see within 300 feet of it to make a DC 18 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes 65 (10d12) force damage and is teleported to an unoccupied space the aspect can see within 20 feet of the aspect. On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage and isn’t teleported.</li>
			</ul>
            <h4 style = "margin-top:10px">Reactions</h4>
            <ul class = "unstyled">
                <li><strong><em>Nip.</em></strong> When a creature ends its turn within 5 feet of the aspect, the aspect makes one Bite attack against that creature.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Goad.</em></strong> When a creature the aspect can see misses an attack roll or fails an ability check or saving throw, the aspect hurls a magically infused insult at that creature. The target must succeed on a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or use its reaction to move its speed toward the aspect. If a creature moves within 5 feet of the aspect in this way, it can make one melee weapon attack against the aspect as a part of its reaction.</li>
                <p></p>
                <li><strong><em>Spell Swallow.</em></strong> When a creature the aspect can see within 120 feet of it casts a spell, the aspect attempts to duplicate that magic for itself. The creature must make a DC 18 Charisma saving throw. On a failure, the spell is cast as usual, but the aspect also casts that same spell as a part of this reaction.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
	</element>
</elements>