<?xml version = "1.0" encoding = "utf-8"?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>College of Hanabi, Bard subclass from Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms</name>
        <update version = "0.0.3">
            <file name = "bard-masks.xml" url = "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/StrangeMeta/homebrew/main/ryokos-guide-to-the-yokai-realms/Classes/Subclasses/bard-masks.xml"/>
        </update>
    </info>

    <!-- College of Masks -->
    <element name = "College of Masks" type = "Archetype" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS">
        <supports>Bard College</supports>
        <description>
            <p class = "flavour">“This mask doesn’t give you power, little girl. This isn’t simple addition! Wearing a mask is an act of transformation. You disappear in its shadow; you become something new—something incredible. That is, of course, if you dare.”</p>
            <p>Masking—the practice of using masks to play a variety of characters in a solo performance—is among the most ancient artistic traditions of the Yokai Realms. Conjuring masks to transform their persona, bards of this college bring tales of fallen heroes, nefarious villains, and epic confrontations to life. Whether on stage or in the heat of battle, such bards perform as a whirling kaleidoscope of character, emotion, and magic, shifting between personas of solitude, war, beauty, and hope.</p>
            <p class = "indent">Some bards of this college see their masks as extensions of their true self, a magnification of their power in a specific direction. Others give themselves completely to the transformation, adopting totally fresh outlooks, personas, and even voices depending on the mask they wear. In either case, each mask grants its own special magic, and with the power to switch between them at will, mask bards have the tools and talents to seize command of any situation.</p>
            <div element = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION"/>
            <div element = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_INSPIRING_PERFORMANCE"/>
            <div element = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_STAGECRAFT"/>
            <div element = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_GRANDIOSE_TRANSFORMATION"/>
        </description>
        <sheet display = "false">
            <description>Masking—the practice of using masks to play a variety of characters in a solo performance—is among the most ancient artistic traditions of the Yokai Realms.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type = "Archetype Feature" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION" level = "3"/>
            <grant type = "Archetype Feature" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_INSPIRING_PERFORMANCE" level = "3"/>
            <grant type = "Archetype Feature" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_STAGECRAFT" level = "6"/>
            <grant type = "Archetype Feature" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_GRANDIOSE_TRANSFORMATION" level = "14"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name = "Kabuki Conjuration" type = "Archetype Feature" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION">
        <description>
            <p>You have the power to conjure magical masks. As a bonus action, you conjure one mask of your choice from the options below. It appears on your face or levitates in the air around you, and it lasts for 1 minute or until you use a bonus action to dismiss it or conjure another one.</p>
            <p class = "indent">While conjured, your mask grants you advantage on Performance checks, and you can use it as a spellcasting focus for your bard spells. The type of mask you conjure also grants an additional benefit:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Mask of Beauty. </strong>When a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see makes a saving throw to resist the effects of an enchantment spell you cast, you can use your reaction to expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration, imposing disadvantage on that roll.</li>
                <li><strong>Mask of Hope. </strong>When a creature within 60 feet of you that can see or hear you rolls a Bardic Inspiration die, you can use your reaction to add your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1) to that roll.</li>
                <li><strong>Mask of Solitude. </strong>When a creature hits you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to release a blast of force from your mask, dealing 1d8 force damage to the creature and pushing it up to 15 feet away from you.</li>
                <li><strong>Mask of War. </strong>You can add your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1) to the damage roll of a weapon attack you make or a bard spell you cast (no action required). You can use this benefit once per turn.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class = "indent">You can create a mask in this way a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest. If you have no uses of this feature remaining, you can create a mask by expending one use of your Bardic Inspiration.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display = "true" usage = "{{kabuki conjuration:usage}}/Long Rest">
            <description>As a bonus action, you conjure one mask of your choice from the options below. It appears on your face or levitates in the air around you, and it lasts for 1 minute or until you use a bonus action to dismiss it or conjure another one. While conjured, your mask grants you advantage on Performance checks, and you can use it as a spellcasting focus for your bard spells. If you have no uses of this feature remaining, you can create a mask by expending one use of your Bardic Inspiration. The type of mask you conjure also grants an additional benefit:</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name = "kabuki conjuration:usage" value = "1" bonus = "base"/>
            <stat name = "kabuki conjuration:usage" value = "charisma:modifier" bonus = "base"/>

            <grant type = "Archetype Feature" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_BEAUTY" requirements = "![level:14]"/>
            <grant type = "Archetype Feature" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_HOPE" requirements = "![level:14]"/>
            <grant type = "Archetype Feature" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_SOLITUDE" requirements = "![level:14]"/>
            <grant type = "Archetype Feature" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_WAR" requirements = "![level:14]"/>
            
            <grant type = "Archetype Feature" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_BEAUTY_ENHANCED" requirements = "[level:14]"/>
            <grant type = "Archetype Feature" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_HOPE_ENHANCED" requirements = "[level:14]"/>
            <grant type = "Archetype Feature" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_SOLITUDE_ENHANCED" requirements = "[level:14]"/>
            <grant type = "Archetype Feature" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_WAR_ENHANCED" requirements = "[level:14]"/>
        </rules>    
    </element>
    <element name = "Mask of Beauty" type = "Archetype Feature" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_BEAUTY">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <sheet display = "true">
            <description>When a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see makes a saving throw to resist the effects of an enchantment spell you cast, you can use your reaction to expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration, imposing disadvantage on that roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Mask of Hope" type = "Archetype Feature" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_HOPE">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <sheet display = "true">
            <description>When a creature within 60 feet of you that can see or hear you rolls a Bardic Inspiration die, you can use your reaction to add your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1) to that roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Mask of Solitude" type = "Archetype Feature" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_SOLITUDE">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <sheet display = "true">
            <description>When a creature hits you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to release a blast of force from your mask, dealing 1d8 force damage to the creature and pushing it up to 15 feet away from you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Mask of War" type = "Archetype Feature" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_WAR">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <sheet display = "true">
            <description>You can add your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1) to the damage roll of a weapon attack you make or a bard spell you cast (no action required). You can use this benefit once per turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Inspiring Performance" type = "Archetype Feature" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_INSPIRING_PERFORMANCE">
        <description>
            <p>You learn to empower others through the art of performance. If you perform for at least 10 minutes, you can choose a number of creatures up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1) who witnessed your performance. Each creature gains temporary hit points equal to your Charisma modifier + your proficiency bonus and has advantage on its next initiative roll before it finishes a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display = "true">
            <description>If you perform for at least 10 minutes, you can choose a number of creatures up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1) who witnessed your performance. Each creature gains temporary hit points equal to your Charisma modifier + your proficiency bonus and has advantage on its next initiative roll before it finishes a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Stagecraft" type = "Archetype Feature" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_STAGECRAFT">
        <description>
            <p>Your mastery of illusions and trickery grants you the power to move yourself and others through space. While you are on the ground or a surface that can support you, you can use a bonus action to target one creature that is no more than one size larger than you within 60 feet of you. That target must succeed on a Charisma saving throw against your bard spell save DC or you both teleport, swapping places. A creature can choose to fail this saving throw.</p>
            <p class = "indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display = "true" usage = "{{stagecraft:usage}}/Long Rest">
            <description>Your mastery of illusions and trickery grants you the power to move yourself and others through space. While you are on the ground or a surface that can support you, you can use a bonus action to target one creature that is no more than one size larger than you within 60 feet of you. That target must succeed on a Charisma saving throw against your bard spell save DC or you both teleport, swapping places. A creature can choose to fail this saving throw.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name = "stagecraft:usage" value = "1" bonus = "base"/>
            <stat name = "stagecraft:usage" value = "charisma:modifier" bonus = "base"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name = "Grandiose Transformation" type = "Archetype Feature" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_GRANDIOSE_TRANSFORMATION">
        <description>
            <p>Your mastery of performance and magic enhances your masks with incredible power. You gain additional benefits depending on the mask you currently have conjured:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Mask of Beauty. </strong>You gain a bonus to all saving throws  equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1).</li>
                <li><strong>Mask of Hope. </strong>When a creature you can see within 90 feet of you falls to 0 hit points but isn’t killed outright, you can use a reaction to expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration. If you do so, the creature is reduced to 1 hit point instead. Once a creature benefits from this feature, it can’t do so again until it finishes a long rest.</li>
                <li><strong>Mask of Solitude. </strong>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</li>
                <li><strong>Mask of War. </strong>If you use your action to cast a spell, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action that turn.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet display = "false"/>
    </element>
    <element name = "Mask of Beauty" type = "Archetype Feature" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_BEAUTY_ENHANCED">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <sheet display = "true">
            <description>When a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see makes a saving throw to resist the effects of an enchantment spell you cast, you can use your reaction to expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration, imposing disadvantage on that roll. You gain a bonus to all saving throws  equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1).</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Mask of Hope" type = "Archetype Feature" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_HOPE_ENHANCED">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <sheet display = "true">
            <description>When a creature within 60 feet of you that can see or hear you rolls a Bardic Inspiration die, you can use your reaction to add your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1) to that roll. When a creature you can see within 90 feet of you falls to 0 hit points but isn’t killed outright, you can use a reaction to expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration. If you do so, the creature is reduced to 1 hit point instead. Once a creature benefits from this feature, it can’t do so again until it finishes a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Mask of Solitude" type = "Archetype Feature" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_SOLITUDE_ENHANCED">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <sheet display = "true">
            <description>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage. When a creature hits you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to release a blast of force from your mask, dealing 1d8 force damage to the creature and pushing it up to 15 feet away from you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Mask of War" type = "Archetype Feature" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_MASKS_KABUKI_CONJURATION_WAR_ENHANCED">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <sheet display = "true">
            <description>You can add your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1) to the damage roll of a weapon attack you make or a bard spell you cast (no action required). You can use this benefit once per turn. If you use your action to cast a spell, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action that turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>