<?xml version = "1.0" encoding = "utf-8"?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Kitsune</name>
        <update version = "0.0.1">
            <file name = "race-kitsune.xml" url = "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/StrangeMeta/homebrew/main/ryokos-guide-to-the-yokai-realms/Races/race-kitsune.xml"/>
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name = "Kitsune" type = "Race" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACE_KITSUNE">
        <description>
            <p class = "flavour">“Ryoko: Any account of the power or grace of kitsune I might write would be grotesquely selfindulgent, so I have requested Bombuku comment on my people in my place.”</p>
            <p class = "flavour">"Bombuku: Yeah, they're chill."</p>
            <p class = "flavour">-Ryoko &amp; Bombuku</p>
            <p>With cautious, padded steps and charcoal nose raised to the air, a kitsune slinks through a twilight forest, indistinguishable from a common fox. The kitsune’s powers of transformation are legendary, being able to assume a fox’s form in a fashion similar to a druid’s mastery of wild shape. Even in their humanoid body, kitsune retain the tail, ears, and clawed feet of their canine cousins, along with a fox’s nimble gait and inquisitive mind. As comfortable in humanoid form as they are as a fox, it is only for the love of interacting with other folk that so many kitsune live their lives almost entirely in their true, bipedal shape, finding it easier to integrate into communities and explore the world in this way.</p>

            <h4>Revered Travellers</h4>
            <p>Long lives, innate curiosity, and a restless drive to understand others lead ancient kitsune to be revered for their wisdom and knowledge. Many act as wandering counsellors and justicars, drawing on a millennium of experience to right the wrongs of the world according to their own perspective. Others focus on a particular branch of research, gaining and spreading knowledge as they travel, or plying their trade as merchants. Such kitsune are able to observe the ebb and flow of supply and demand across generations, wielding their experience and long lives as tools in the acquisition of incredible wealth.</p>

            <h4>KITSUNE TRAITS</h4>
            <p>As a kitsune, you have the following traits:</p>
            <p>
                <span class = "feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and your Dexterity increases by 1.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Age. </span>Kitsune mature at the same rate as humans, reaching adulthood at around 20. They can go on to live up to a millennium.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Size. </span>You are Medium. Fully grown kitsune stand between 5-6 feet tall.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Speed. </span>Your walking speed is 35 feet.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Creature Type. </span>You are a Humanoid.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Ascendant Form. </span>You have the power to take on a magical, ascendant form. As an action, you can radiate bright, white light for 1 minute or until you end the effect as a bonus action. This light penetrates magical darkness, shedding bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. Creatures of your choice in the light can add 1d4 to their Charisma (Persuasion) checks, Wisdom (Perception) checks, and initiative rolls. Once you use this trait, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Darkvision. </span>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern colour in darkness, only shades of grey.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Fox's Wedding. </span>You know the druidcraft and produce flame cantrips. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells (choose when you select this race).<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Kitsune Guile. </span>You have proficiency in the Deception and Stealth skills.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Language of Motion. </span>You can articulate ideas through motion, as well as speech. If you spend 1 minute moving your tails and ears, you can communicate a simple message, which can be contrary to any words you may be speaking aloud. This communication is undetectable to any creature that doesn’t speak Kitsune. A creature within 30 feet of you that can see you and speaks Kitsune can understand this message.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Shapeshifter. </span>As an action, you can transform into the shape of a fox. When you do, your clothing and equipment meld into your form, and you gain no benefits from them while transformed. You determine the specifics of your appearance in fox form, including your colouration and size (choosing from Tiny or Small when you transform). All your other game statistics remain the same. You can’t cast spells that require material or somatic components while in this form, but you can still concentrate on spells and speak as normal. You remain in this form until you use an action to revert to your true form or you die.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Languages. </span>You can speak, read, and write Common, Kitsune, and one other language that you and your GM agree is appropriate for your character.<br/>
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display = "true"/>
        <rules>
            <stat name = "charisma" value = "2" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI"/>
            <stat name = "dexterity" value = "1" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI"/>
            <select type = "Ability Score Improvement" name = "Ablity Score Improvement Option (Kitsune)" supports = "Custom Ability Score Improvement Option" requirements = "ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI"/>
            <grant type = "Size" id = "ID_SIZE_MEDIUM"/>
            <stat name = "innate speed" value = "35" bonus = "base"/>

            <grant type = "Creature Type" id = "ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_TYPE_HUMANOID"/>

            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_ASCENDANT_FORM"/>
            <grant type = "Vision" id = "ID_VISION_DARKVISION"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_FOXS_WEDDING"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_KITSUNES_GUILE"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_LANGUAGE_OF_MOTION"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_SHAPESHIFTER"/>

            <grant type = "Language" id = "ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE"/>
            <grant type = "language" id = "ID_RGTTYR_LANGUAGE_KITSUNE" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE"/>
            <select type = "Language" name = "Language (Kitsune)" supports = "Standard||Exotic"/>

        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name = "Ascendant Form" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_ASCENDANT_FORM">
        <description>
            <p>You have the power to take on a magical, ascendant form. As an action, you can radiate bright, white light for 1 minute or until you end the effect as a bonus action. This light penetrates magical darkness, shedding bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. Creatures of your choice in the light can add 1d4 to their Charisma (Persuasion) checks, Wisdom (Perception) checks, and initiative rolls. Once you use this trait, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage = "1/Long Rest">
            <description>You have the power to take on a magical, ascendant form. As an action, you can radiate bright, white light for 1 minute or until you end the effect as a bonus action. This light penetrates magical darkness, shedding bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. Creatures of your choice in the light can add 1d4 to their Charisma (Persuasion) checks, Wisdom (Perception) checks, and initiative rolls. Once you use this trait, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Fox's Wedding" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_FOXS_WEDDING">
        <description>
            <p>You know the druidcraft and produce flame cantrips.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You know the druidcraft and produce flame cantrips.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type = "Spell" id = "ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT"/>
            <grant type = "Spell" id = "ID_PHB_SPELL_PRODUCE_FLAME"/>
            <select type = "Racial Trait" supports = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_FOXS_WEDDING_INTELLIGENCE|ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_FOXS_WEDDING_WISDOM|ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_FOXS_WEDDING_CHARISMA"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <!-- Spellcasting options for Fox's Wedding -->
    <element name = "Intelligence" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_FOXS_WEDDING_INTELLIGENCE">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <description>
            <p>You know the druidcraft and produce flame cantrips. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Wisdom" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_FOXS_WEDDING_WISDOM">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <description>
            <p>You know the druidcraft and produce flame cantrips. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Charisma" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_FOXS_WEDDING_CHARISMA">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <description>
            <p>You know the druidcraft and produce flame cantrips. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name = "Kitsune's Guile" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_KITSUNES_GUILE">
        <description>
            <p>You have proficiency in the Deception and Stealth skills.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have proficiency in the Deception and Stealth skills.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<grant type = "Proficiency" id = "ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<select type = "Proficiency" name = "Customized Skill Proficiency" supports = "Skill" requirements = "ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<grant type = "Proficiency" id = "ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<select type = "Proficiency" name = "Customized Skill Proficiency" supports = "Skill" requirements = "ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name = "Language of Motion" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_LANGUAGE_OF_MOTION">
        <description>
            <p>You can articulate ideas through motion, as well as speech. If you spend 1 minute moving your tails and ears, you can communicate a simple message, which can be contrary to any words you may be speaking aloud. This communication is undetectable to any creature that doesn’t speak Kitsune. A creature within 30 feet of you that can see you and speaks Kitsune can understand this message.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can articulate ideas through motion, as well as speech. If you spend 1 minute moving your tails and ears, you can communicate a simple message, which can be contrary to any words you may be speaking aloud. This communication is undetectable to any creature that doesn’t speak Kitsune. A creature within 30 feet of you that can see you and speaks Kitsune can understand this message.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Shapeshifter" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_SHAPESHIFTER">
        <description>
            <p>As an action, you can transform into the shape of a fox. When you do, your clothing and equipment meld into your form, and you gain no benefits from them while transformed. You determine the specifics of your appearance in fox form, including your colouration and size (choosing from Tiny or Small when you transform). All your other game statistics remain the same. You can’t cast spells that require material or somatic components while in this form, but you can still concentrate on spells and speak as normal. You remain in this form until you use an action to revert to your true form or you die.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As an action, you can transform into the shape of a fox. When you do, your clothing and equipment meld into your form, and you gain no benefits from them while transformed. You determine the specifics of your appearance in fox form, including your colouration and size (choosing from Tiny or Small when you transform). All your other game statistics remain the same. You can’t cast spells that require material or somatic components while in this form, but you can still concentrate on spells and speak as normal. You remain in this form until you use an action to revert to your true form or you die.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name = "Kitsune" type = "Language" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_LANGUAGE_KITSUNE">
        <supports>Exotic</supports>
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name = "exotic">true</set>
            <set name = "speakers">Kitsune</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>