<?xml version = "1.0" encoding = "utf-8"?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Tengu</name>
        <update version = "0.0.1">
            <file name = "race-tengu.xml" url = "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/StrangeMeta/homebrew/main/ryokos-guide-to-the-yokai-realms/Races/race-tengu.xml"/>
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name = "Tengu" type = "Race" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACE_TENGU">
        <description>
            <p class = "flavour">She stood before me as a paradox, both of and beyond this world, terrifying and elegant, wise as a kitsune elder and puckish as a fuyohren child. I felt my tails quiver, my legs shake, my breath catch, and my heart overflow with relief. For now, I was safe. If the tengu mean you harm, you’re dead long before they can be seen.</p>
            <p>In the sprawling forests that clothe the land from frosty mountainside to fertile shore, verdant life is cultivated and protected by a race of aloof guardians: the tengu.</p>
            <p class = "indent">Mischievous, prideful, and territorial, tengu are a race of long-lived yokai. They make their home in the treetops, nimbly navigating precarious pathways as noiselessly as a shadow passes along the forest floor. Although typically reclusive, younger tengu have a sparkling curiosity toward the outside world, taking earnest interest in those who visit their domain. To all who trespass, however, a subtle threat is ever present. Harm not the forest, lest the wrath of the tengu fall like a crushing oak.</p>

            <h4>Yokai Warriors</h4>
            <p>As yokai, tengu are innately magical. Their natural powers lean towards trickery and illusion, allowing them to strike both the mind and body in a dazzling battery of lethal force. To many tengu, swordplay is a way of life—both a meditative practice and a form of self-defence. The resolute tengu swordmaster, a crackling visage of shadowy magic and slashing steel, is one found throughout the folklore and legends of many other peoples.</p>

            <h4>The Tengu Code</h4>
            <p>Ryōkido have a long, living history, borne on a stream of shared memory and experience. They find great value in family and community, raising pups as a village, and viewing those they surround themselves with as extensions of themselves. To the ryōkido, every friend is family, every family a village, every village a legion. When moved to action, a single ryōkido walks as an army.</p>

            <h4>TENGU TRAITS</h4>
            <p>As a tengu, you have the following traits:</p>
            <p>
                <span class = "feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>Your Dexterity score increases by 2.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Age. </span>Tengu reach maturity at around 16 years of age, and go on to live for up to 400 years.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Size. </span>You are Medium. Tengu are typically a little larger than humans, standing between 6 and 7 feet tall.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Speed. </span>Your walking speed is 30 feet.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Creature Type. </span>You are a Humanoid.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Lethal Masters. </span>You have proficiency with one simple or martial weapon of your choice.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Languages. </span>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your GM agree is appropriate for your character.<br/>
            </p>
                <div element = "ID_RGTTYR_RACE_VARIANT_TENGU_HANATAKU"/>
                <div element = "ID_RGTTYR_RACE_VARIANT_TENGU_KARASU"/>
        </description>
        <sheet display = "true"/>
        <rules>
            <stat name = "strength" value = "2" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI"/>
            <select type = "Ability Score Improvement" name = "Ablity Score Improvement Option (Lion Turtle)" supports = "Custom Ability Score Improvement Option" requirements = "ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI"/>
            <grant type = "Size" id = "ID_SIZE_MEDIUM"/>
            <stat name = "innate speed" value = "30" bonus = "base"/>

            <grant type = "Creature Type" id = "ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_TYPE_HUMANOID"/>

            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_LETHAL_MASTERS"/>

            <grant type = "Language" id = "ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE"/>
            <select type = "Language" name = "Language (Tengu)" supports = "Standard||Exotic"/>

            <select type = "Race Variant" name = "Tengu Variant" supports = "ID_RGTTYR_RACE_VARIANT_TENGU_HANATAKU|ID_RGTTYR_RACE_VARIANT_TENGU_KARASU"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name = "Lethal Masters" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realm" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_LETHAL_MASTERS">
        <description>
            <p>You have proficiency with one simple or martial weapon of your choice.</p>
        </description>
        <rules>
            <select type = "Proficiency" supports = "Weapon"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <!-- Tengu subraces -->
    <element name = "Hanataku Tengu" type = "Race Variant" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACE_VARIANT_TENGU_HANATAKU">
        <supports>Tengu</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Less ferocious and impulsive than the karasu, hanataka are widely regarded as the “higher” lineage of tengu. With the patience and tenacity of a flowing river, they live, train, and meditate in the towering trees of their mountain home. Hanataka tengu are swiftly provoked by vanity and are quick to humble the arrogant and foolish. To those who show respect, however, elder hanataka tengu make sage counsellors and guides, imparting the wisdom of age and yokai magic. Legend tells that the great warriors of old honed their swiftness of blade and sharpness of mind under the guidance of hanataka masters.</p>
            <p>
                <span class = "feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>Your Charisma score increases by 1.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Master of Craft. </span>You are proficient with one kind of artisan’s tools of your choice. When you make a Crafting check using this tool, you can add 1d4 to the result of the check.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Nature Guardian. </span>You gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Arcana, Nature, Religion, Stealth, or Survival.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Shadow Caster. </span>You learn the prestidigitation and thaumaturgy cantrips. In addition, you can cast them without components while you are in dim light or darkness. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells when you cast them with this trait (choose when you select this race).<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Whirlwind Onslaught. </span>After you take the Attack action on your turn, you can use your bonus action on that turn to cast a cantrip with a casting time of one action or make a number of melee attacks equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded up). Each of these attacks must target a different creature. Once you use this trait, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.<br/>
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display = "true"/>
        <rules>
            <stat name = "charisma" value = "1" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_HANATAKU_MASTER_OF_CRAFT"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_HANATAKU_NATURE_GUARDIAN"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_HANATAKU_SHADOW_CASTER"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIR_TENGU_HANATAKU_WHIRLWIND_ONSLAUGHT"/>
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name = "Master of Craft" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_HANATAKU_MASTER_OF_CRAFT">
        <description>
            <p>You are proficient with one kind of artisan’s tools of your choice. When you make a Crafting check using this tool, you can add 1d4 to the result of the check.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You are proficient with one kind of artisan’s tools of your choice. When you make a Crafting check using this tool, you can add 1d4 to the result of the check.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type = "Proficiency" name = "Tool Proficiency (Hanataku)" supports = "Artisan tools"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name = "Nature Guardian" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_HANATAKU_NATURE_GUARDIAN">
        <description>
            <p>You gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Arcana, Nature, Religion, Stealth, or Survival.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display = "false"/>
        <rules>
            <select type = "Proficiency" name = "Tengu (Nature Guardian)" supports = "ID_SKILL_PROFICIENCY_ARCANA|ID_SKILL_PROFICIENCY_NATURE|ID_SKILL_PROFICIENCY_RELIGION|ID_SKILL_PROFICIENCY_STEALTH|ID_SKILL_PROFICIENCY_SURVIVAL"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name = "Shadow Caster" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_HANATAKU_SHADOW_CASTER">
        <description>
            <p>You learn the prestidigitation and thaumaturgy cantrips. In addition, you can cast them without components while you are in dim light or darkness. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells when you cast them with this trait (choose when you select this race).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You learn the prestidigitation and thaumaturgy cantrips. In addition, you can cast them without components while you are in dim light or darkness.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type = "Spell" id = "ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION"/>
            <grant type = "Spell" id = "ID_PHB_SPELL_THAUMATURGY"/>
            <select type = "Racial Trait" name = "Spellcasting (Shadow Caster)" supports = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_HANATAKU_SHADOW_CASTER_INTELLIGENCE|ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_HANATAKU_SHADOW_CASTER_WISDOM|ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_HANATAKU_SHADOW_CASTER_CHARISMA"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name = "Intelligence" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_HANATAKU_SHADOW_CASTER_INTELLIGENCE">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <description>
            <p>Intelligence is your spellcasting modifier for this ability.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Intelligence is your spellcasting modifier for this ability.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Wisdom" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_HANATAKU_SHADOW_CASTER_WISDOM">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <description>
            <p>Wisdom is your spellcasting modifier for this ability.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Wisdom is your spellcasting modifier for this ability.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Charisma" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_HANATAKU_SHADOW_CASTER_CHARISMA">
        <compendium display = "false"/>
        <description>
            <p>Charisma is your spellcasting modifier for this ability.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Charisma is your spellcasting modifier for this ability.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name = "Karasu Tengu" type = "Race Variant" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACE_VARIANT_TENGU_KARASU">
        <supports>Tengu</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Deceptive and witty, cunning and dangerous, karasu tengu are tricksters at heart. They take great joy in pranks, be they simple or elaborate, and cackle gleefully at the humbling of others. Karasu have many avian qualities, including vestigial, feathered wings and powerful, snapping beaks. As bursting with life as their forest homes, and as volatile and passionate as the tempestuous winds, the friendship of a karasu is one of staunch trust and joy. Those who insult them, however, find karasu grudges run long, deep, and deadly.</p>

            <p>
                <span class = "feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>Your Wisdom score increases by 1.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Fortified Mind. </span>You have resistance to psychic damage.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Prankster. </span>You gain proficiency in the Deception and Stealth skills.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Psychic Battery. </span>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with a dizzying psychic assault against a creature you can see within 15 feet of you. That creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC equals 8 + your Constitution modifier + your proficiency bonus) or suffer the effects of the confusion spell until the end of its next turn. Once you use this trait, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Skyrider. </span>When you fall at least 10 feet and aren’t incapacitated, you can use your reaction to extend your vestigial, feathered wings to glide. You take no damage from that fall, and you can move horizontally 2 feet for every 1 foot you fall.<br/>
            </p>
            <div element = "ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION"/>
        </description>
        <sheet display = "true"/>
        <rules>
            <stat name = "wisdom" value = "1" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_KARASU_FORTIFIED_MIND"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_KARASU_PRANKSTER"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_KARASU_PSYCHIC_BATTERY"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_KARASU_SKYRIDER"/>
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name = "Fortified Mind" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_KARASU_FORTIFIED_MIND">
        <description>
            <p>You have resistance to psychic damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have resistance to psychic damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type = "Condition" id = "ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name = "Prankster" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_KARASU_PRANKSTER">
        <description>
            <p>You gain proficiency in the Deception and Stealth skills.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain proficiency in the Deception and Stealth skills.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY"/>
            <select type = "Proficiency" supports = "Skill" requirements = "ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY"/>
            <select type = "Proficiency" supports = "Skill" requirements = "ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name = "Psychic Battery" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_KARASU_PSYCHIC_BATTERY">
        <description>
            <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with a dizzying psychic assault against a creature you can see within 15 feet of you. That creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC equals 8 + your Constitution modifier + your proficiency bonus) or suffer the effects of the confusion spell until the end of its next turn. Once you use this trait, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            <div element = "ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION"/>
        </description>
        <sheet usage = "1/Long Rest">
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one of your attacks with a dizzying psychic assault against a creature you can see within 15 feet of you. That creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC equals 8 + your Constitution modifier + your proficiency bonus) or suffer the effects of the confusion spell until the end of its next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Skyrider" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_TENGU_KARASU_SKYRIDER">
        <description>
            <p>When you fall at least 10 feet and aren’t incapacitated, you can use your reaction to extend your vestigial, feathered wings to glide. You take no damage from that fall, and you can move horizontally 2 feet for every 1 foot you fall.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you fall at least 10 feet and aren’t incapacitated, you can use your reaction to extend your vestigial, feathered wings to glide. You take no damage from that fall, and you can move horizontally 2 feet for every 1 foot you fall.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>