<?xml version = "1.0" encoding = "utf-8"?>
<elements>
    <!-- <info>
        <name>Hanamori</name>
        <description></description>
        <author>Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms</author>
        <update version = "0.0.1">
            <file name = "race-hanamori.xml" url = ""/>
        </update>
    </info> -->

    <element name = "Hanamori" type = "Race" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACE_HANAMORI">
        <description>
            <p class = "flavour">I was told the hanamori were born from the molten slag of a bleeding mountain, life bursting forth from the cruellest environment imaginable. Others say they bloomed from the first corpses cut down in war, or emerged fully formed from the silent, chill void. There are one hundred stories of how they came to be, but no matter which you choose to believe, in every tale one theme runs true: the hanamori are life born from death.</p>
            <p>With gaunt faces, charcoal skin, and coarse crimson petals, hanamori are a race of sentient plants believed by many to be harbingers of death. This reputation is not wholly unfounded, for hanamori are physiologically sympathetic; their bodies reverberate in harmony with the fleeting spirit of creatures that die in their presence, taking on traits of the deceased for a short time. The slaughter of a mighty beast is felt by its hunters as a surge of physical strength, and the passing of a sage as a transcendent moment of heightened wisdom. As a result, hanamori have a complex relationship with death; to die in their presence is to pass a glimpse of oneself to another, for a short time.</p>

            <h4>Reactive Physiology</h4>
            <p>A hanamori’s sympathetic physiology extends to the world around them. While they can briefly share in the physiology of creatures who die, they can permanently take on the physical characteristics of their environment over a longer duration. Humid jungles might impart a hanamori with a permanent scent of rich flora, while icy mountains cause their body to forever be chill to the touch. Hanamori adventurers who travel the world end their lives as a collage of the habitats that succored them, a jigsaw infused with environmental memories ever bonded to their form.</p>

            <h4>Burning Emotions</h4>
            <p>Hanamori are naturally passionate and active. They think, speak, and adapt swiftly, and are known for their fiery tempers and zealous loyalty. With short lives, hanamori see little value in holding grudges or overanalysing a situation, preferring to think on their feet and revel in the heat of each moment. A hanamori’s emotional state can be read on its body: its petals blush darkly when enraged, and the tips of its branches sprout new buds during periods of prolonged grief. It is said that if a hanamori loses a true love, it will forever bloom.</p>

            <h4>HANAMORI TRAITS</h4>
            <p>As a hanamori, you have the following traits:</p>
            <p>
                <span class = "feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and your Wisdom increases by 1.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Age. </span>Hanamori reach adulthood at the same rate as humans and go on to live for up to 60 years.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Size. </span>Hanamori vary in size—you can be Medium or Small. You choose the size when you select this race.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Speed. </span>Your walking speed is 30 feet.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Creature Type. </span>You are a Plant.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Essence Capture. </span>You have the power to magically capture fragments of a creature’s power when it dies in your proximity. As a reaction when a creature with a CR equal to or lower than your level dies within 10 feet of you, you can capture a fragment of its essence. You gain one of the following effects of your choice:<br/>
                <ul>
                    <li>You replace your Strength, Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma ability score with the same ability score of the creature that died.</li>
                    <li>You gain one special sense of your choice, except truesight, that the creature possessed, out to the same range.</li>
                    <li>You gain resistance to one damage type of your choice to which the creature had resistance or immunity.</li>
                    <li>You gain immunity to one condition of your choice, except exhaustion, to which the creature had immunity.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class = "indent">This effect lasts for 1 hour, after which time you return to normal. Once you use this trait, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                <span class = "feature">Fiery Countenance. </span>You have advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the frightened or stunned condition on yourself.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Gaze of Death. </span>You gain proficiency in your choice of one of the following skills: Intimidation, Medicine, Nature, or Survival.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Rugged. </span>Your tough, lignified exterior is a natural barrier to cuts and abrasions. When you aren’t wearing armour, your AC is 12 + your Constitution modifier. You can use your natural armour to determine your AC if the armour you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield’s benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armour.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Languages. </span>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your GM agree is appropriate for your character.<br/>
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display = "true"/>
        <rules>
            <stat name = "charisma" value = "2" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI"/>
            <stat name = "wisdom" value = "1" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI"/>
            <select type = "Ability Score Improvement" name = "Ablity Score Improvement Option (Hanamori)" supports = "Custom Ability Score Improvement Option" requirements = "ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI"/>
            <select type = "Racial Trait" name = "Size (Hanamori)" supports = "ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_SMALL|ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_MEDIUM"/>
            <stat name = "innate speed" value = "30" bonus = "base"/>

            <grant type = "Creature Type" id = "ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_TYPE_PLANT"/>

            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_HANAMORI_ESSENCE_CAPTURE"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_HANAMORI_FIERY_COUNTENANCE"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_HANAMORI_GAZE_OF_DEATH"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_HANAMORI_RUGGED"/>

            <grant type = "Language" id = "ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE"/>
            <select type = "Language" name = "Language (Hanamori)" supports = "Standard||Exotic"/>

        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name = "Essence Capture" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_HANAMORI_ESSENCE_CAPTURE">
            <description>
                <p>You have the power to magically capture fragments of a creature’s power when it dies in your proximity. As a reaction when a creature with a CR equal to or lower than your level dies within 10 feet of you, you can capture a fragment of its essence. You gain one of the following effects of your choice:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You replace your Strength, Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma ability score with the same ability score of the creature that died.</li>
                    <li>You gain one special sense of your choice, except truesight, that the creature possessed, out to the same range.</li>
                    <li>You gain resistance to one damage type of your choice to which the creature had resistance or immunity.</li>
                    <li>You gain immunity to one condition of your choice, except exhaustion, to which the creature had immunity.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        <sheet usage = "1/Long Rest">
            <description>
                <p>You have the power to magically capture fragments of a creature’s power when it dies in your proximity. As a reaction when a creature with a CR equal to or lower than your level dies within 10 feet of you, you can capture a fragment of its essence. You gain one of the following effects of your choice:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You replace your Strength, Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma ability score with the same ability score of the creature that died.</li>
                    <li>You gain one special sense of your choice, except truesight, that the creature possessed, out to the same range.</li>
                    <li>You gain resistance to one damage type of your choice to which the creature had resistance or immunity.</li>
                    <li>You gain immunity to one condition of your choice, except exhaustion, to which the creature had immunity.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Fiery Countenance" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_HANAMORI_FIERY_COUNTENANCE">
        <description>
            <p>You have advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the frightened or stunned condition on yourself.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on saving throws you make to avoid or end the frightened or stunned condition on yourself.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Gaze of Death" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_HANAMORI_GAZE_OF_DEATH">
        <description>
            <p>You gain proficiency in your choice of one of the following skills: Intimidation, Medicine, Nature, or Survival.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain proficiency in your choice of one of the following skills: Intimidation, Medicine, Nature, or Survival.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type = "Proficiency" name = "Skill Proficiency (Hanamori)" supports = "Skill, Hanamori Gaze of Death"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <!-- Skills for Gaze of Death -->
    <append id = "ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
        <supports>Hanamori Gaze of Death</supports>
    </append>
    <append id = "ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
        <supports>Hanamori Gaze of Death</supports>
    </append>
    <append id = "ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
        <supports>Hanamori Gaze of Death</supports>
    </append>
    <append id = "ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL">
        <supports>Hanamori Gaze of Death</supports>
    </append>
    <element name = "Rugged" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_HANAMORI_RUGGED">
        <description>
            <p>Your tough, lignified exterior is a natural barrier to cuts and abrasions. When you aren’t wearing armour, your AC is 12 + your Constitution modifier. You can use your natural armour to determine your AC if the armour you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield’s benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armour.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your tough, lignified exterior is a natural barrier to cuts and abrasions. When you aren’t wearing armour, your AC is 12 + your Constitution modifier. You can use your natural armour to determine your AC if the armour you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield’s benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armour.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name = "hanamori:natural barrier" value = "12" bonus = "base"/>
            <stat name = "hanamori:natural barrier" value = "constitution:modifier" bonus = "ability"/>
            <stat name = "ac:calculation" value = "hanamori:natural barrier" bonus = "calculation" alt = "Natural Barrier (Hanamori)"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>