<?xml version = "1.0" encoding = "utf-8"?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Isetsu</name>
        <update version = "0.0.1">
            <file name = "race-isetsu.xml" url = "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/StrangeMeta/ryokos-guide-to-the-yokai-realms/main/Races/race-isetsu.xml"/>
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name = "Isetsu" type = "Race" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACE_ISETSU">
        <description>
            <p class = "flavour">Isetsu are warriors, but we do not live for war. We live for that which our battles defend</p>
            <p>Along stoney, shattered cliffs, blasted by howling wind and icy rain, the isetsu stand guard. A race of large, crustacean-like Humanoids, isetsu have made a home facing the ocean for millenia, thriving and hunting beneath the open waves, and resting on the shore. Although they do not swim as nimbly as nishikin or ryujin, the isetsu’s superior eyesight, towering bodies, and resolute carapace serve them well in the deep; they are the undisputed rulers of the cliffs and seabeds.</p>

            <h4>Shoreline Guardians</h4>
            <p>It is said that at the dawn of the world, isetsu were tasked with the defence of the land against the roiling sea. All manner of horrors dwell in the black void of the ocean depths, and core to the isetsu way of life is the shared, endless responsibility to stand watch on the shore. All isetsu train in combat, and all feel an aching longing to face the ocean. Even isetsu that travel the world, shirking their divine responsibility, feel this pull, and the reverberation of an isetsu’s heartbeat through its carapace mimics the gentle lapping of waves on the shore—a whisper to return home. This is the isetsu’s burden: to be in love with the ocean, yet tasked to defend against it. They are the first line of defence against any threat that rises from the sea, be it pirate, typhoon, or kaiju.</p>

            <h4>Fortune Favoured</h4>
            <p>Isetsu hold a deterministic philosophy: just as their destiny was set at the dawn of the world, so are others beating an inevitable path, whether they realise it or not. To the isetsu, luck is a complex, measurable science, and good fortune is a talent that can be trained, a skill they dedicate endless hours to mastering. Many tales of incredible, serendipitous events occurring in favour of the isetsu seem to indicate this training holds worth. Even the most sceptical members of other races begrudgingly accept that the isetsu come up “lucky” in battle at a rate far beyond any other creature. A common idiom across the reams, referring to an incredible stroke of good fortune, is “an isetsu’s million-to-one”.</p>
            
            <h4>ISETSU TRAITS</h4>
            <p>As an isetsu, you have the following traits:</p>
            <p>
                <span class = "feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Constitution increases by 1.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Age. </span>Isetsu grow swiftly, reaching adulthood in less than a decade, and they go on to live for up to a century.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Size. </span>You are Medium. Isetsu stand taller than most Humanoids, averaging around 7 feet in height.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Speed. </span>Your walking speed is 30 feet.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Creature Type. </span>You are a Humanoid.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Brittle Shell. </span>Your carapace has a brittle, but tough, outer layer that regenerates over time. When you finish a short or long rest, you gain a +2 bonus to AC if you don’t already have this bonus. This bonus ends after you are hit by an attack roll.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Crustacean Physiology. </span>Your antennae aid you in keeping watch, and your natural bulk and size serve you well in contests of strength. You gain proficiency in the Athletics and Perception skills.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Claws. </span>You have claws that you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike. Starting at 5th level, when you hit a creature with an unarmed strike on your turn, you can immediately use a bonus action to attempt to grapple it.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Darkvision. </span>Accustomed to the deep blackness of the ocean floor, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern colour in darkness, only shades of grey.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Favoured Warrior. </span>Be it sheer dumb luck, the result of intense training, or the fruition of a divine blessing, you have an uncanny ability to find fortune in combat. If you miss an attack roll, or fail an ability check or saving throw, you can reroll the attack roll, check, or save with advantage. You can use this trait a number of times equal to half your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Natural Armour. </span>Your shell acts as a natural source of protection. When you aren’t wearing armour, your base AC is 12 + your Constitution modifier. You can use your natural armour to determine your AC if the armour you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield’s benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armour.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Waterborne. </span>You can breathe in both air and water. Additionally, being underwater doesn’t impose disadvantage on your weapon attack rolls.<br/>
                <span class = "feature">Languages. </span>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language that you and your GM agree is appropriate for your character.<br/>
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display = "true"/>
        <rules>
            <stat name = "strength" value = "2" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI"/>
            <stat name = "constitution" value = "1" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI"/>
            <select type = "Ability Score Improvement" name = "Ablity Score Improvement Option (Isetsu)" supports = "Custom Ability Score Improvement Option" requirements = "ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI"/>
            <grant type = "Size" id = "ID_SIZE_MEDIUM"/>
            <stat name = "innate speed" value = "30" bonus = "base"/>

            <grant type = "Creature Type" id = "ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_TYPE_HUMANOID"/>

            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_ISESTU_BRITTLE_SHELL"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_ISETSU_CRUSTACEAN_PHYSIOLOGY"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_ISETSU_CLAWS"/>
            <grant type = "Vision" id = "ID_VISION_DARKVISION"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_ISETSU_FAVOURED_WARRIOR"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_ISETSU_NATURAL_ARMOUR"/>
            <grant type = "Racial Trait" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_ISETSU_WATERBORNE"/>

            <grant type = "Language" id = "ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" requirements = "!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE"/>
            <select type = "Language" name = "Language (Isetsu)" supports = "Standard||Exotic"/>

        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name = "Brittle Shell" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_ISESTU_BRITTLE_SHELL">
        <description>
            <p>Your carapace has a brittle, but tough, outer layer that regenerates over time. When you finish a short or long rest, you gain a +2 bonus to AC if you don’t already have this bonus. This bonus ends after you are hit by an attack roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your carapace has a brittle, but tough, outer layer that regenerates over time. When you finish a short or long rest, you gain a +2 bonus to AC if you don’t already have this bonus. This bonus ends after you are hit by an attack roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Crustacean Physiology" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_ISETSU_CRUSTACEAN_PHYSIOLOGY">
        <description>
            <p>Your antennae aid you in keeping watch, and your natural bulk and size serve you well in contests of strength. You gain proficiency in the Athletics and Perception skills.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your antennae aid you in keeping watch, and your natural bulk and size serve you well in contests of strength. You gain proficiency in the Athletics and Perception skills.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Customized Skill Proficiency" supports="Skill" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Customized Skill Proficiency" supports="Skill" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name = "Claws" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_ISETSU_CLAWS">
        <description>
            <p>You have claws that you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike. Starting at 5th level, when you hit a creature with an unarmed strike on your turn, you can immediately use a bonus action to attempt to grapple it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have claws that you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike. Starting at 5th level, when you hit a creature with an unarmed strike on your turn, you can immediately use a bonus action to attempt to grapple it.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Favoured Warrior" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_ISETSU_FAVOURED_WARRIOR">
        <description>
            <p>Be it sheer dumb luck, the result of intense training, or the fruition of a divine blessing, you have an uncanny ability to find fortune in combat. If you miss an attack roll, or fail an ability check or saving throw, you can reroll the attack roll, check, or save with advantage. You can use this trait a number of times equal to half your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage = "{{proficiency:half}}/Long Rest">
            <description>Be it sheer dumb luck, the result of intense training, or the fruition of a divine blessing, you have an uncanny ability to find fortune in combat. If you miss an attack roll, or fail an ability check or saving throw, you can reroll the attack roll, check, or save with advantage. You can use this trait a number of times equal to half your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name = "Natural Armour" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_ISETSU_NATURAL_ARMOUR">
        <description>
            <p>Your shell acts as a natural source of protection. When you aren’t wearing armour, your base AC is 12 + your Constitution modifier. You can use your natural armour to determine your AC if the armour you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield’s benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armour.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your shell acts as a natural source of protection. When you aren’t wearing armour, your base AC is 12 + your Constitution modifier. You can use your natural armour to determine your AC if the armour you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield’s benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armour.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name = "isetsu:natural armour" value = "12" bonus = "base"/>
            <stat name = "isetsu:natural armour" value = "constitution:modifier" bonus = "ability"/>
            <stat name = "ac:calculation" value = "isetsu:natural armour" bonus = "calculation" alt = "Natural Armour (Isetsu)"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name = "Waterborne" type = "Racial Trait" source = "Ryoko's Guide to the Yokai Realms" id = "ID_RGTTYR_RACIAL_TRAIT_ISETSU_WATERBORNE">
        <description>
            <p>You can breathe in both air and water. Additionally, being underwater doesn’t impose disadvantage on your weapon attack rolls.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can breathe in both air and water. Additionally, being underwater doesn’t impose disadvantage on your weapon attack rolls.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>